[{"questionNumber":1,"question":"_____ three languages: French, Spanish, and English.\r\n","options":{"A":" I’m speak ","B":" I’m speaking\r\n","C":" I speaking ","D":" I speak"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":2,"question":"Where _____ from?\r\n","options":{"A":" Hans come ","B":" does Hans come\r\n","C":" does Hans coming ","D":" Hans came"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":3,"question":"What _____ tonight?\r\n","options":{"A":" do you do ","B":" you do\r\n","C":" are you doing ","D":" did you do"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":4,"question":"“Where is George”\r\n“He _____ a shower.”\r\n","options":{"A":" has ","B":" will have ","C":" is having ","D":" have"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":5,"question":"“What _____ ?”\r\n“I don’t know. Look it up.”\r\n","options":{"A":" does this word mean ","B":" means this word\r\n","C":" does mean this word ","D":" is meaning this word"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":6,"question":"“Do you want a cigarette?”\r\n“No, thanks. I _____ .”\r\n","options":{"A":" no smoke ","B":" smoke not\r\n","C":" am not smoking ","D":" don’t smoke"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":7,"question":"Last year I _____ to America.\r\n","options":{"A":" was go ","B":" go ","C":" was going ","D":" went"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":8,"question":"How long _____ in America?\r\n","options":{"A":" you stay ","B":" did you stay\r\n","C":" stayed you ","D":" you staying"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":9,"question":"The weekend was boring. I _____ anything.\r\n","options":{"A":" don’t do ","B":" no do\r\n","C":" didn’t do ","D":" wasn’t doing"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":10,"question":"“I’m going to university next year”\r\n“What _____ study?”\r\n","options":{"A":" you going to ","B":" do you\r\n","C":" did you ","D":" are you going to\r\nEnrique __(11)__ in Puebla, a town in Mexico. He __(12)__ medicine\r\nbecause he __(13)__ to be a doctor. He’s married, but he __(14)__\r\nany children. His wife, Silvia, __(15)__ in a primary school. Enrique\r\n__(16)__ cooking. He can make an excellent enchilada!"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":11,"question":"","options":{"A":" lived ","B":" lives\r\n","C":" was living ","D":" live"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":12,"question":"","options":{"A":" studied ","B":" was studying\r\n","C":" is studying ","D":" doesn’t study"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":13,"question":"","options":{"A":" is wanting ","B":" was wanting\r\n","C":" will want ","D":" wants"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":14,"question":"","options":{"A":" has ","B":" have\r\n","C":" doesn’t have ","D":" is going to have"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":15,"question":"","options":{"A":" was teaching ","B":" teaches\r\n","C":" teach ","D":" thought"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":16,"question":"","options":{"A":" loved ","B":" used to love\r\n","C":" loves ","D":" love"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":17,"question":"At the weekend, I usually _____ go swimming.\r\n","options":{"A":" am ","B":" *\r\n","C":" was ","D":" want"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":18,"question":"Are you _____ the party?\r\n","options":{"A":" enjoy ","B":" enjoyed ","C":" enjoying ","D":" enjoys"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":19,"question":"How many sisters _____ ?\r\n","options":{"A":" do you have ","B":" you have\r\n","C":" are you have ","D":" do you has"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":20,"question":"I _____ understand what you are saying.\r\n","options":{"A":" no ","B":" don’t ","C":" am not ","D":" didn’t"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":21,"question":"What time _____ home last night?\r\n","options":{"A":" did you get ","B":" you get\r\n","C":" do you get ","D":" did you got"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":22,"question":"Last weekend I _____ some friends and we _____ a meal.\r\n","options":{"A":" see / having ","B":" saw / have\r\n","C":" seeing / had ","D":" saw / had"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":23,"question":"I _____ English food. It’s wonderful!\r\n","options":{"A":" am loving ","B":" loved ","C":" love ","D":" loves"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":24,"question":"Pierre is French. He _____ from Toulouse.\r\n","options":{"A":" is coming ","B":" came ","C":" come ","D":" comes"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":25,"question":"_____ the computer at the moment?\r\n","options":{"A":" Does Mr. Taylor use ","B":" Is Mr. Taylor using\r\n","C":" Did Mr. Taylor use ","D":" Will Mr. Taylor use"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":26,"question":"Dave _____ a student with her work now.\r\n","options":{"A":" helped ","B":" help ","C":" is helping ","D":" helping"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":27,"question":"“ It’s very noisy”\r\n“Suzy _____ to rock music.”\r\n","options":{"A":" listen ","B":" listens ","C":" listened ","D":" is listening"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":28,"question":"Carol _____ hard for her exam last week.\r\n","options":{"A":" didn’t study ","B":" isn’t studying\r\n","C":" don’t study ","D":" aren’t study"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":29,"question":"Most of the students _____ these days.\r\n","options":{"A":" didn’t smoke ","B":" aren’t smoking\r\n","C":" isn’t smoking ","D":" don’t smoke"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":30,"question":"You look nice, Anne. _____ a new dress?\r\n","options":{"A":" Do you wear ","B":" Does she wear\r\n","C":" Are you wearing ","D":" Did you wear"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":31,"question":"Many birds _____ south every winter.\r\n","options":{"A":" fly ","B":" flew ","C":" are flying ","D":" will fly"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":32,"question":"Usually Jim _____ to work on Saturdays.\r\n","options":{"A":" is going ","B":" went ","C":" go ","D":" goes"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":33,"question":"Japan _____ many high mountains.\r\n","options":{"A":" have ","B":" is having ","C":" has ","D":" are having"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":34,"question":"Cats _____ very well in darkness.\r\n","options":{"A":" are seeing ","B":" see ","C":" will ","D":" sees"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":35,"question":"“What _____ ?”\r\n“I’m studying computer science.”\r\n","options":{"A":" are you studying ","B":" were you studying\r\n","C":" was you studying ","D":" is she studying"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":36,"question":"“ _____ born?”\r\n“I was born in London.”\r\n","options":{"A":" When did you ","B":" Where were you\r\n","C":" Where are you ","D":" Where do you"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":37,"question":"“Are _____?”\r\n“No, I’m single.”\r\n","options":{"A":" he marries ","B":" you married\r\n","C":" you marry ","D":" she married"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":38,"question":"“ _____ a job ?”\r\n“No, I don’t. I’m a student.”\r\n","options":{"A":" Did you have ","B":" Do you have\r\n","C":" Have you had ","D":" Are you having"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":39,"question":"“_____ Liverpool?”\r\n“It’s in the north west of England.”\r\n","options":{"A":" Where were ","B":" Where are\r\n","C":" Where is ","D":" When was"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":40,"question":"“What _____?”\r\n“My name’s Ben.”\r\n","options":{"A":" was your name ","B":" were your name\r\n","C":" is your name ","D":" is his name"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":41,"question":"“Are _____ your course?”\r\n“Yes, I’m enjoying it very much.”\r\n","options":{"A":" you enjoying ","B":" they enjoying\r\n","C":" they enjoyed ","D":" enjoying"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":42,"question":"“Do _____ clubs?”\r\n“I go sometimes.”\r\n","options":{"A":" you do ","B":" you go to\r\n","C":" you usually go ","D":" you do go to"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":43,"question":"“What_____ doing in you free time?”\r\n“I like watching sport on TV.”\r\n","options":{"A":" are you ","B":" sport are you\r\n","C":" do you like ","D":" would you like to"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":44,"question":"“ _____”\r\n“Yes, can I help you?”\r\n","options":{"A":" Thank you! ","B":" Cheers!\r\n","C":" Excuse me! ","D":" Nothing much."},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":45,"question":"“What are you doing this weekend?”\r\n“______________.”\r\n","options":{"A":" Nothing much ","B":" Not at all. Don’t mention it\r\n","C":" Cheers ","D":" Bye for now"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":46,"question":"“Make your self at home.”\r\n“ _____ .”\r\n","options":{"A":" Sleep well ","B":" Thank you\r\n","C":" Thanks. Same to you ","D":" Excuse me"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":47,"question":"“Thank you so much for helping.”\r\n“ _____ .”\r\n","options":{"A":" Nothing much ","B":" Cheers\r\n","C":" Not at all. Don’t mention it ","D":" Sleep well"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":48,"question":"“Good morning!”\r\n“ _____”\r\n","options":{"A":" Good morning! ","B":" Thank you!\r\n","C":" Cheers! ","D":" Sleep well!"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":49,"question":"“See you next week.”\r\n“ ___________. “\r\n","options":{"A":" Cheers ","B":" Thank you\r\n","C":" Good morning ","D":" Bye for now"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":50,"question":"“Have a nice day!”\r\n“ _____.”\r\n","options":{"A":" Thanks. Same to you ","B":" Not at all. Don’t mention it.\r\n","C":" Nothing much ","D":" Sleep well"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":51,"question":"A- Where _____ from?\r\nB- _____ am from Milano.\r\n","options":{"A":" are you / I ","B":" are / you\r\n","C":" are they / they ","D":" you / I"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":52,"question":"A- _____ Leo eat Chinese food?\r\nB- Yes, he _____ it _____ he was 10.\r\n","options":{"A":" Did / eaten / when ","B":" Does / ate / what\r\n","C":" Did / ate / when ","D":" Do / eat / what"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":53,"question":"What _____ they going _____ do?\r\n","options":{"A":" are / too ","B":" are / to ","C":" is / to ","D":" is / too"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":54,"question":"A- How _____ languages can your son speak?\r\nB- Three _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" much / languages ","B":" many / language\r\n","C":" many / languages ","D":" much / language"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":55,"question":"A- When _____ it _____ raining?\r\nB- Yesterday.\r\n","options":{"A":" Did / started ","B":" Does / start\r\n","C":" Does / starts ","D":" Did / start"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":56,"question":"_____ kind _____ music do you like?\r\n","options":{"A":" What / * ","B":" How / of ","C":" What / of ","D":" What / *"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":57,"question":"A- Good night!\r\nB - _____!\r\n","options":{"A":" Sleep well ","B":" Cheers ","C":" Fine, thanks ","D":" Bye"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":58,"question":"Oh! Welcome, Jack! __________.\r\n","options":{"A":" Pleased to meet you ","B":" That’s very kind\r\n","C":" Make yourself at home ","D":" Same to you"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":59,"question":"Customer: _______________!\r\nShop assistant: _______________?\r\n","options":{"A":" Good morning / Good morning\r\n","B":" Excuse me / Yes, can I help you\r\n","C":" Bless you / Thank you\r\n","D":" How do you do / How do you do"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":60,"question":"A- Thank you very much!\r\nB- ___________.\r\n","options":{"A":" Same to you ","B":" Thanks\r\n","C":" Bye ","D":" Not at all"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":61,"question":"Mobile phones, televisions, and radios are a means of _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" communication ","B":" transport\r\n","C":" media ","D":" civilization"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":62,"question":"Romans _____ a unique system of the Roman alphabet.\r\n","options":{"A":" improved ","B":" developed\r\n","C":" persuaded ","D":" exchanged"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":63,"question":"Nowadays media has a huge influence on the _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" neighbors ","B":" society\r\n","C":" printing pressing ","D":" Greeks"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":64,"question":"We send _____ through the internet.\r\n","options":{"A":" a letter ","B":" a fax ","C":" mail ","D":" an e-mail"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":65,"question":"Romans, Greek and Egyptians are all _____ nations.\r\n","options":{"A":" ancient ","B":" old ","C":" dated ","D":" modern\r\n"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":66,"question":"Where _____ on holidays?\r\n","options":{"A":" you go ","B":" do you go\r\n","C":" do you going ","D":" are you go"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":67,"question":"I _____ to work now. Good-bye!\r\n","options":{"A":" go ","B":" went ","C":" am going ","D":" goes"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":68,"question":"I _____ a book about astrology these days.\r\n","options":{"A":" am reading ","B":" read ","C":" am reads ","D":" reading"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":69,"question":"I _____ lots of books every year.\r\n","options":{"A":" will read ","B":" am reading\r\n","C":" read ","D":" am going to read"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":70,"question":"Nurses _____ after people in hospital.\r\n","options":{"A":" looks ","B":" is looking ","C":" will look ","D":" look"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":71,"question":"Annie _____ from Ireland.\r\n","options":{"A":" come ","B":" is coming ","C":" comes ","D":" coming"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":72,"question":"We _____ to a party next Saturday.\r\n","options":{"A":" go ","B":" goes ","C":" are going ","D":" went"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":73,"question":"She _____ for dinner this evening.\r\n","options":{"A":" come ","B":" came ","C":" comes ","D":" is coming"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":74,"question":"_____ to go out tonight?\r\n","options":{"A":" Do you want ","B":" Are you wanting\r\n","C":" Is you want ","D":" Would you want"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":75,"question":"I _____ four languages.\r\n","options":{"A":" am speaking ","B":" speak\r\n","C":" speaks ","D":" am speak"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":76,"question":"Every morning Tessa _____ at 7.30.\r\n","options":{"A":" is getting up ","B":" got up\r\n","C":" get up ","D":" gets up"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":77,"question":"Oh, someone _____ in my seat!\r\n","options":{"A":" is sitting ","B":" sits ","C":" will sit ","D":" sit"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":78,"question":"I’m sorry. I can’t help you at the moment. I _____ dinner.\r\n","options":{"A":" will cook ","B":" am cooking ","C":" cook ","D":" cooked"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":79,"question":"I _____ a pain in my leg.\r\n","options":{"A":" has ","B":" having ","C":" have ","D":" am having"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":80,"question":"Mrs. Steele _____ to her boss. I’ll tell her you phoned.\r\n","options":{"A":" talked ","B":" talks ","C":" talk ","D":" is talking"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":81,"question":"Turn the T.V off. No one _____ it!\r\n","options":{"A":" watches ","B":" watch ","C":" is watching ","D":" watched"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":82,"question":"She is not ready. She _____ her hair.\r\n","options":{"A":" is washing ","B":" washes ","C":" washed ","D":" wash"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":83,"question":"Derek’s good at golf but he _____ very often.\r\n","options":{"A":" aren’t play ","B":" isn’t playing ","C":" doesn’t play ","D":" didn’t play"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":84,"question":"The sun _____ in the day time.\r\n","options":{"A":" shine ","B":" shone ","C":" is shining ","D":" shines"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":85,"question":"In Britain people _____ on the right.\r\n","options":{"A":" are driving ","B":" drives ","C":" drive ","D":" drove"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":86,"question":"This is a great party! Everyone _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" dance ","B":" is dancing ","C":" dances ","D":" are dancing"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":87,"question":"Jack’s a policeman but he _____ a uniform.\r\n","options":{"A":" doesn’t wear ","B":" isn’t wearing\r\n","C":" no wear ","D":" wears"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":88,"question":"What _____ in your free time?\r\n","options":{"A":" are you doing ","B":" do you do\r\n","C":" you do ","D":" are you do"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":89,"question":"How many children _____?\r\n","options":{"A":" are you having ","B":" do you have\r\n","C":" do you have got ","D":" are you have"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":90,"question":"I _____ a shower every morning.\r\n","options":{"A":" have got ","B":" am having ","C":" have ","D":" has\r\nMy sister and I are very different, __(26)__ we get on well together.\r\nShe likes staying at home in the evening __(27)__ watching television\r\nwith parents. __(28)__ I prefer going out with my friends. We like to\r\ngo to clubs or the cinema. Sometimes we just go to a café. I have\r\nexams soon, __(29)__ I’m not going out very much these days. My\r\nsister is six years older than me, __(30)__ she works in a bank. She’s\r\ntrying to save some money __(31)__ she’s going to get married this\r\nyear. Her fiancé’s name is Ferdinand. __(32)__, we all call him Freddy.\r\nPeople say I look like my sister __(33)__ we both have brown eyes\r\n__(34)__ dark hair. __(35)__, we are very different in character. She’s\r\nvery quiet, __(36)__ I’m a lot more sociable."},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":91,"question":"","options":{"A":" and ","B":" but ","C":" so ","D":" because"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":92,"question":"","options":{"A":" however ","B":" so ","C":" and ","D":" because"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":93,"question":"","options":{"A":" Because ","B":" And ","C":" So ","D":" But"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":94,"question":"","options":{"A":" so ","B":" however ","C":" but ","D":" and"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":95,"question":"","options":{"A":" however ","B":" so ","C":" because ","D":" and"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":96,"question":"","options":{"A":" and ","B":" so ","C":" because ","D":" but"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":97,"question":"","options":{"A":" However ","B":" So ","C":" But ","D":" And"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":98,"question":"","options":{"A":" so ","B":" because ","C":" and ","D":" however"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":99,"question":"","options":{"A":" but ","B":" so ","C":" however ","D":" and"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":100,"question":"","options":{"A":" But ","B":" So ","C":" However ","D":" And"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":101,"question":"","options":{"A":" however ","B":" but ","C":" and ","D":" so"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":102,"question":"I _____ a bicycle when I was young.\r\n","options":{"A":" have ","B":" am having ","C":" had ","D":" have got"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":103,"question":"He_____ a shower in the morning.\r\n","options":{"A":" have got ","B":" has ","C":" am having ","D":" have"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":104,"question":"He _____ milk in his coffee.\r\n","options":{"A":" never has ","B":" has never got\r\n","C":" has never ","D":" have never"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":105,"question":"What time _____ lunch in general?\r\n","options":{"A":" does you have ","B":" have you got\r\n","C":" do you have ","D":" are you having"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":106,"question":"The Pope _____ in Vatican.\r\n","options":{"A":" live ","B":" lived ","C":" lives ","D":" will live\r\n"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":107,"question":"I was born in Africa _____ 1970.\r\n","options":{"A":" on ","B":" at ","C":" in ","D":" last"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":108,"question":"My parents moved back to England _____ I was five.\r\n","options":{"A":" when ","B":" ago ","C":" * ","D":" for"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":109,"question":"We lived in Bristol _____ three years.\r\n","options":{"A":" last ","B":" for ","C":" at ","D":" *"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":110,"question":"I left college three years _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" nothing ","B":" ago ","C":" for ","D":" in"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":111,"question":"I found a flat on my own _____ last year.\r\n","options":{"A":" at ","B":" for ","C":" * ","D":" on"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":112,"question":"I usually go home _____ the weekend.\r\n","options":{"A":" in ","B":" when ","C":" at ","D":" of"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":113,"question":"I didn’t go home ____ weekend because some friends came to stay.\r\n","options":{"A":" for ","B":" last ","C":" * ","D":" at"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":114,"question":"They arrived _____ three o’clock _____ the afternoon.\r\n","options":{"A":" at / in ","B":" in / for ","C":" when / ago ","D":" last / *"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":115,"question":"_____ Saturday evening we went out to a concert.\r\n","options":{"A":" Last ","B":" In ","C":" For ","D":" On"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":116,"question":"_____ we got home we listened to some music.\r\n","options":{"A":" For ","B":" Last ","C":" Last ","D":" When"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":117,"question":"We got up late _____ Sunday morning.\r\n","options":{"A":" * ","B":" at ","C":" on ","D":" in"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":118,"question":"_____ the afternoon we went for a walk.\r\n","options":{"A":" At ","B":" For ","C":" On ","D":" In"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":119,"question":"I bought a car a few weeks _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" last ","B":" when ","C":" ago ","D":" for"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":120,"question":"I had an accident _____ last night.\r\n","options":{"A":" in ","B":" * ","C":" on ","D":" at"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":121,"question":"It happened _____ seven o’clock _____ the evening.\r\n","options":{"A":" when / * ","B":" in / at ","C":" at / last ","D":" at / in"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":122,"question":"I took my car to the garage _____ this morning.\r\n","options":{"A":" in ","B":" when ","C":" * ","D":" at"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":123,"question":"It will be ready _____ two weeks.\r\n","options":{"A":" * ","B":" in ","C":" on ","D":" for"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":124,"question":"I _____ a friend while I _____ the shopping\r\n","options":{"A":" was meeting / did ","B":" met / was doing\r\n","C":" meet / do ","D":" met / did"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":125,"question":"I _____ for my things when I ____ someone call my name.\r\n","options":{"A":" paid / was hearing ","B":" pay / heard\r\n","C":" was paying / hear ","D":" was paying / heard"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":126,"question":"I _____ round and _____ Paula.\r\n","options":{"A":" turned / saw ","B":" was turning/ was seeing\r\n","C":" turn / was seeing ","D":" was turning / saw"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":127,"question":"She _____ a bright red coat yesterday.\r\n","options":{"A":" wore ","B":" was wearing\r\n","C":" wear ","D":" was wear"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":128,"question":"We _____ to have a cup of coffee.\r\n","options":{"A":" decided ","B":" were deciding\r\n","C":" decides ","D":" will deciding"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":129,"question":"While we _____ a drink, a waiter _____ a pile of plates.\r\n","options":{"A":" had / was dropping ","B":" have / dropped\r\n","C":" have / drop ","D":" were having / dropped"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":130,"question":"We all _____ a terrible shock.\r\n","options":{"A":" were getting ","B":" gets\r\n","C":" getting ","D":" got"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":131,"question":"While the waiter _____ up the broken plates, he _____ his finger.\r\n","options":{"A":" picked / was cutting ","B":" was picking / cut\r\n","C":" pick / cut ","D":" picks / cut\r\nThis morning I __(26)__ to work. I __(27)__ to go by bus because\r\nthe sun __(28)__. While I __(29)__ past the supermarket, I __(30)__\r\nsomething strange. A man __(31)__ near me and he __(32)__ a\r\nsong very loudly on his own! He __(33)__ for a few minutes. Then\r\nhe __(34)__ a friend and he __(35)__ singing."},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":132,"question":"","options":{"A":" was walking ","B":" walked ","C":" walk ","D":" walking"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":133,"question":"","options":{"A":" didn’t want ","B":" wasn’t wanting\r\n","C":" don’t want ","D":" am not wanting"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":134,"question":"","options":{"A":" shone ","B":" is shining ","C":" was shining ","D":" shines"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":135,"question":"","options":{"A":" walked ","B":" am walking ","C":" was walked ","D":" was walking"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":136,"question":"","options":{"A":" was seeing ","B":" saw ","C":" am seeing ","D":" see"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":137,"question":"","options":{"A":" passed ","B":" was passing ","C":" pass ","D":" passes"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":138,"question":"","options":{"A":" sang ","B":" sing ","C":" was singing ","D":" song"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":139,"question":"","options":{"A":" was continuing ","B":" continues\r\n","C":" is continuing ","D":" continued"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":140,"question":"","options":{"A":" will met ","B":" met ","C":" was meeting ","D":" meet"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":141,"question":"","options":{"A":" was stopping ","B":" stop\r\n","C":" stopped ","D":" is stopping"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":142,"question":"I _____ a very good program on TV last night.\r\n","options":{"A":" was seeing ","B":" see ","C":" am seeing ","D":" saw"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":143,"question":"While I _____ this morning, I _____ my money. I don’t know how.\r\n","options":{"A":" shopped / lose ","B":" was shopping / lost\r\n","C":" shopped / was losing ","D":" shop / lose"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":144,"question":"Last week the police _____ Alan in his car because he _____ over\r\neighty miles an hour.\r\n","options":{"A":" were stopping / was driving\r\n","B":" stop / drived\r\n","C":" stopped / was driving\r\n","D":" was stopping / drove"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":145,"question":"How _____ your finger?\r\n","options":{"A":" are you cutting ","B":" were you cutting\r\n","C":" did you cut ","D":" you cut"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":146,"question":"I _____ and I _____ the knife.\r\n","options":{"A":" cooked / was dropping ","B":" cook / drop\r\n","C":" was cooking / dropped ","D":" cooked / dropped"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":147,"question":"When I _____ at the party, everyone _____ a good time.\r\n","options":{"A":" was arriving / had ","B":" arrived / was having\r\n","C":" arrived / had ","D":" arrived / were having"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":148,"question":"_____ a good time last night?\r\n","options":{"A":" Did you have ","B":" Were you having\r\n","C":" Will you have ","D":" Are you having"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":149,"question":"While I _____ to work this morning I _____ an old friend.\r\n","options":{"A":" went / meet ","B":" am going / met\r\n","C":" go / was meeting ","D":" was going / met"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":150,"question":"I _____ to get up this morning. It _____ and it was cold, and my bed\r\nwas so warm.\r\n","options":{"A":" don’t want / is raining ","B":" am not wanting / rains\r\n","C":" wasn’t wanting / rained ","D":" didn’t want / was raining"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":151,"question":"I _____ to the news on the radio when the phone _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" listened / was ringing ","B":" am listening / was ringing\r\n","C":" was listening / rang ","D":" listen / is ringing"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":152,"question":"But when I _____ up the phone, there was no one there.\r\n","options":{"A":" pick ","B":" am picking ","C":" picked ","D":" was picking"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":153,"question":"I _____ hello to the children, but they didn’t say anything because\r\nthey _____ television.\r\n","options":{"A":" say / watched ","B":" said / were watching\r\n","C":" was / saying ","D":" said / watched"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":154,"question":"What _____ at 8.00 last night?\r\n","options":{"A":" did you do ","B":" you did\r\n","C":" were you doing ","D":" are you doing"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":155,"question":"We played tennis _____ two hours.\r\n","options":{"A":" during ","B":" while ","C":" nothing ","D":" for"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":156,"question":"I worked on a farm _____ the holidays.\r\n","options":{"A":" for ","B":" since ","C":" while ","D":" on\r\n"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":157,"question":"A: Did you meet _____ at the party?\r\nB: Yes, I met _____ who knows you!\r\n","options":{"A":" someone / anyone ","B":" anything / nobody\r\n","C":" anybody / somebody ","D":" everybody / nothing"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":158,"question":"A: Ouch! There’s _____ in my eye!\r\nB: Let me look. No, I can’t see _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" something / anything ","B":" anything / anywhere\r\n","C":" somebody / everywhere ","D":" something / nothing"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":159,"question":"A: Let’s go _____ hot for our holidays.\r\nB: But we can’t go _____; that’s too expensive.\r\n","options":{"A":" everywhere / nowhere ","B":" somewhere / anywhere\r\n","C":" anywhere / everywhere ","D":" anybody / someone"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":160,"question":"A: I don’t want to talk to _____.\r\nB: And I want to talk to _____ either.\r\n","options":{"A":" anyone / no one ","B":" somebody / everyone\r\n","C":" nobody / somebody ","D":" everybody/anybody"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":161,"question":"I lost my glasses. I looked _____, but I couldn’t find them.\r\n","options":{"A":" anywhere ","B":" everywhere\r\n","C":" somewhere ","D":" everything"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":162,"question":"A: Did you buy _____ at the shops?\r\nB: No,_____. I didn’t have any money.”\r\n","options":{"A":" something / anything ","B":" everything / something\r\n","C":" anything / nothing ","D":" no one / anybody"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":163,"question":"It was a great party. _____ loved it.\r\n","options":{"A":" Everything ","B":" Anyone\r\n","C":" Somebody ","D":" Everybody"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":164,"question":"I’m bored. I want _____ interesting to read, or ____ to talk to, or\r\n____ interesting to go.\r\n","options":{"A":" anything / everyone / something\r\n","B":" somebody / anyone / anywhere\r\n","C":" something / somebody / somewhere\r\n","D":" everything / nobody / somewhere"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":165,"question":"Have you got _____ homework?\r\n","options":{"A":" many ","B":" much ","C":" a few ","D":" some"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":166,"question":"We don’t need _____ eggs. Just half a dozen.\r\n","options":{"A":" a little ","B":" many ","C":" much ","D":" a few"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":167,"question":"Is there _____ traffic in your town?\r\n","options":{"A":" a few ","B":" many ","C":" some ","D":" much"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":168,"question":"I have _____ close fiends. Two or three.\r\n","options":{"A":" a lot of ","B":" a little ","C":" a few ","D":" much"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":169,"question":"I don’t know _____ students in this class. Because I am a newcomer.\r\n","options":{"A":" many ","B":" a few ","C":" some ","D":" much"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":170,"question":"How _____ people live in your house?\r\n","options":{"A":" any ","B":" much ","C":" many ","D":" a lot of"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":171,"question":"He has _____ money. He’s a millionaire.\r\n","options":{"A":" many ","B":" a lot of ","C":" a little ","D":" a lot"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":172,"question":"A: Do you take sugar in coffee?”\r\nB: Just _____. Half a spoonful.”\r\n","options":{"A":" a few ","B":" many ","C":" a little ","D":" a lot of"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":173,"question":"A: Have you got _____ CD’s?\r\nB: Yes, hundreds.\r\n","options":{"A":" much ","B":" a little ","C":" a few ","D":" lots of"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":174,"question":"I’ll be ready in _____ minutes.\r\n","options":{"A":" a lot ","B":" a little ","C":" much ","D":" a few"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":175,"question":"She speaks good Spanish, but only _____ Russian.\r\n","options":{"A":" a few ","B":" a lot of ","C":" much ","D":" a little"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":176,"question":"I come to ______ school by _____ bus.\r\n","options":{"A":" * / the ","B":" the / a ","C":" * / * ","D":" the / the"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":177,"question":"This morning _____ bus was late.\r\n","options":{"A":" a ","B":" * ","C":" an ","D":" the"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":178,"question":"My favorite subject is _____ history, but I’m not very good at _____\r\nmath.\r\n","options":{"A":" * / the ","B":" a / a ","C":" the / the ","D":" * / *"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":179,"question":"Ankara is _____ capital of Turkey.\r\n","options":{"A":" the ","B":" a ","C":" * ","D":" an"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":180,"question":"I work in _____ company that makes _____ carpets.\r\n","options":{"A":" a / * ","B":" the / the ","C":" the / * ","D":" a / a"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":181,"question":"My friend lives in _____ same street as me.\r\n","options":{"A":" a ","B":" * ","C":" an ","D":" the"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":182,"question":"A: How much are the driving lessons?\r\nB: Fifteen pounds _____ hour.\r\n","options":{"A":" * ","B":" the ","C":" an ","D":" a"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":183,"question":"I was at _____ home all day yesterday.\r\n","options":{"A":" the ","B":" * ","C":" an ","D":" a"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":184,"question":"There are _____ apples.\r\n","options":{"A":" most ","B":" a lot of ","C":" a little ","D":" much"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":185,"question":"The shop hasn’t got _____ washing powder.\r\n","options":{"A":" a few ","B":" few ","C":" much ","D":" many"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":186,"question":"Why aren’t there _____ magazines?\r\n","options":{"A":" little ","B":" much ","C":" a little ","D":" many"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":187,"question":"The shop hasn’t got _____ birthday cards.\r\n","options":{"A":" many ","B":" much ","C":" some ","D":" a little"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":188,"question":"I saw _____ change on the table a minute ago.\r\n","options":{"A":" much ","B":" some ","C":" many ","D":" any"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":189,"question":"I can see _____ newspapers.\r\n","options":{"A":" lots of ","B":" most ","C":" a little ","D":" much"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":190,"question":"The shopkeeper has got _____ cheese.\r\n","options":{"A":" a lot of ","B":" many ","C":" few ","D":" a few"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":191,"question":"I need _____ help with my homework. Are you free?\r\n","options":{"A":" a few ","B":" much ","C":" any ","D":" some"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":192,"question":"Let’s have _____ ice-cream.\r\n","options":{"A":" a ","B":" * ","C":" an ","D":" the"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":193,"question":"I eat _____ apple every day.\r\n","options":{"A":" the ","B":" a ","C":" an ","D":" *"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":194,"question":"Would you like _____ coffee or tea?\r\n","options":{"A":" * ","B":" the ","C":" an ","D":" a"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":195,"question":"They don’t like _____ chocolate.\r\n","options":{"A":" a ","B":" the ","C":" * ","D":" an"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":196,"question":"I’d like _____ glass of milk, please.\r\n","options":{"A":" the ","B":" a ","C":" an ","D":" *"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":197,"question":"Please have _____ cake.\r\n","options":{"A":" a ","B":" * ","C":" the ","D":" an"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":198,"question":"How often do you eat _____ chocolate?\r\n","options":{"A":" the ","B":" an ","C":" * ","D":" a"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":199,"question":"This table is made of _____ glass.\r\n","options":{"A":" * ","B":" the ","C":" an ","D":" a"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":200,"question":"I never drink _____ coffee.\r\n","options":{"A":" an ","B":" * ","C":" a ","D":" the"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":201,"question":"Does he like _____ cake?\r\n","options":{"A":" the ","B":" a ","C":" an ","D":" *"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":202,"question":"She needs _____ to help her choose a birthday present.\r\n","options":{"A":" something ","B":" anybody ","C":" someone ","D":" somewhere"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":203,"question":"Is _____ listening to me!\r\n","options":{"A":" somebody ","B":" anyone ","C":" something ","D":" anywhere"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":204,"question":"Would _____ please explain what happened?\r\n","options":{"A":" anything ","B":" somewhere ","C":" anybody ","D":" someone"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":205,"question":"He doesn’t care. He will watch _____ on television!\r\n","options":{"A":" somewhere ","B":" something ","C":" anything ","D":" anybody"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":206,"question":"If _____ asks, tell them I’ve got a cold.\r\n","options":{"A":" anyone ","B":" anything ","C":" somewhere ","D":" somebody\r\n"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":207,"question":"“_____ a drink?”\r\n“Yes, please. I’ll have an orange juice.”\r\n","options":{"A":" Do you like ","B":" Are you liking\r\n","C":" Would you like ","D":" Did you like"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":208,"question":"“What _____ at the weekend?”\r\n“I like putting my feet up and relaxing. Sometimes I play tennis.”\r\n","options":{"A":" will you like to do ","B":" do you like doing\r\n","C":" would you like to do ","D":" are you like to do"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":209,"question":"“_____ your teacher?”\r\n“Yes, she’s very nice.”\r\n","options":{"A":" Did you like ","B":" Would you like\r\n","C":" Will you like ","D":" Do you like"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":210,"question":"“What _____ to do in the evening?”\r\n“Why don’t we pop round and see Pat and Peter?”\r\n","options":{"A":" do you like ","B":" are you\r\n","C":" would you like ","D":" did you like"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":211,"question":"“_____ for walks?”\r\n“What a good idea! It’s so hot today!”\r\n","options":{"A":" Are you going to go ","B":" Did you like going\r\n","C":" Do you like going ","D":" Would you like to go"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":212,"question":"“My bag is so heavy.”\r\n“Give it to me. _____ it for you.”\r\n","options":{"A":" I’m going to carry ","B":" I carry\r\n","C":" I’ll carry ","D":" I carried"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":213,"question":"I bought some warm boots today because _____ skiing.\r\n","options":{"A":" I went ","B":" I’m going ","C":" I’ll go ","D":" I go"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":214,"question":"“Tony’s back from holiday.”\r\n“_____ him a ring.”\r\n","options":{"A":" I’ll give ","B":" I gave\r\n","C":" I’m going give ","D":" I give"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":215,"question":"“What are you doing tonight?”\r\n“We _____ a play at the theatre.”\r\n","options":{"A":" saw ","B":" will see\r\n","C":" are going to see ","D":" seeing"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":216,"question":"You can tell me your secret. I _____ anyone.\r\n","options":{"A":" am not going tell ","B":" won’t tell\r\n","C":" don’t tell ","D":" didn’t tell"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":217,"question":"“I need to post these letters.”\r\n“I _____ shopping soon. I _____ them for you.”\r\n","options":{"A":" will go / will post ","B":" am going / will post\r\n","C":" am going / am going post ","D":" go / am going to post"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":218,"question":"“Now, holidays. Where _____ this year?”\r\n“We don’t know yet.”\r\n","options":{"A":" did you go ","B":" you going\r\n","C":" will you go ","D":" do you going"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":219,"question":"We’ve decided _____ married in the spring.\r\n","options":{"A":" get ","B":" to get ","C":" getting ","D":" got"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":220,"question":"I hope _____ some money soon.\r\n","options":{"A":" earning ","B":" earn ","C":" to earn ","D":" to earning"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":221,"question":"I want _____ a film on TV this evening.\r\n","options":{"A":" seeing ","B":" see ","C":" see to ","D":" to see"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":222,"question":"Some people like _____ breakfast in bed, but I don’t.\r\n","options":{"A":" having ","B":" too have ","C":" have ","D":" had"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":223,"question":"I’m looking forward _____ you again soon.\r\n","options":{"A":" to see ","B":" seeing ","C":" to seeing ","D":" see"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":224,"question":"I _____ my job soon.\r\n","options":{"A":" think changing ","B":" am thinking of changing\r\n","C":" am thinking to change ","D":" think change"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":225,"question":"This book is full _____ pictures.\r\n","options":{"A":" with ","B":" in ","C":" to ","D":" of"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":226,"question":"Julie is married _____ Sam.\r\n","options":{"A":" in ","B":" with ","C":" to ","D":" at"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":227,"question":"I don’t agree _____ him.\r\n","options":{"A":" for ","B":" at ","C":" with ","D":" to"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":228,"question":"He isn’t good _____ French.\r\n","options":{"A":" at ","B":" in ","C":" to ","D":" of"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":229,"question":"My brother is interested _____ math.\r\n","options":{"A":" to ","B":" in ","C":" of ","D":" at"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":230,"question":"Look _____ those birds!\r\n","options":{"A":" at ","B":" to ","C":" for ","D":" in"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":231,"question":"Are you afraid _____ flying?\r\n","options":{"A":" with ","B":" at ","C":" in ","D":" of"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":232,"question":"Wait _____ me in the street.\r\n","options":{"A":" to ","B":" for ","C":" at ","D":" in"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":233,"question":"Bill is looking _____ his keys but he can’t find them.\r\n","options":{"A":" for ","B":" at ","C":" to ","D":" in"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":234,"question":"Please ask _____ help if you want.\r\n","options":{"A":" to ","B":" for ","C":" of ","D":" in"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":235,"question":"Do you work _____ someone special?\r\n","options":{"A":" at ","B":" for ","C":" of ","D":" in"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":236,"question":"Can I speak _____ you for a minute?\r\n","options":{"A":" with ","B":" of ","C":" at ","D":" for"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":237,"question":"Barbara hopes _____ a lawyer.\r\n","options":{"A":" become ","B":" to become ","C":" of becoming ","D":" becoming"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":238,"question":"I’d love ____ with you.\r\n","options":{"A":" to going ","B":" go ","C":" to go ","D":" going"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":239,"question":"She enjoys _____ the news on television.\r\n","options":{"A":" watching ","B":" to watch ","C":" to watching ","D":" watch"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":240,"question":"I’m looking forward _____ more free time.\r\n","options":{"A":" to having ","B":" to have ","C":" of having ","D":" having"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":241,"question":"Do you want _____ it again?\r\n","options":{"A":" try ","B":" trying ","C":" to trying ","D":" to try"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":242,"question":"We’re _____ a party next Saturday. Would you like _____?\r\n","options":{"A":" have / to go ","B":" having / to come\r\n","C":" had / to have ","D":" having to / had"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":243,"question":"You must see my new flat. ____ round and _____ a drink some time.\r\n","options":{"A":" Go / come ","B":" Have / come\r\n","C":" Go / have ","D":" Come / have"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":244,"question":"“I _____ out now, Mum. Bye!”\r\n“OK. Have a good time. What time _____ home?”\r\n","options":{"A":" went / did you come ","B":" am going / are you coming\r\n","C":" go / will you come ","D":" am going / do you come"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":245,"question":"Hi, Dave. Pete _____ a shower at the moment. I’ll just _____ and tell\r\nhim.\r\n","options":{"A":" is having / go ","B":" had / went\r\n","C":" is having / come ","D":" will have / will go"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":246,"question":"“I feel nervous. I’ve got an exam today.”\r\n“_______________”\r\n","options":{"A":" Cheer up! Things can’t be that bad!\r\n","B":" That’s great. Have a good time.\r\n","C":" Poor you! That happens to me sometimes.\r\n","D":" Good luck! Do your best."},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":247,"question":"“I feel really depressed at the moment. Nothing’s going right in my\r\nlife.”\r\n“_____”\r\n","options":{"A":" I know. We really need some sunshine, don’t we?\r\n","B":" Cheer up! Things can’t be that bad!\r\n","C":" I’m sorry to hear that, but I’m sure he’ll be all right.\r\n","D":" That’s good. I’m pleased to hear it."},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":248,"question":"“I’m really excited. I’m going on holiday to Australia tomorrow.\r\n“_____”\r\n","options":{"A":" Good luck! Do your best.\r\n","B":" Why don’t you go home to bed?\r\n","C":" That’s great. Have a good time.\r\n","D":" Cheer up! Things can’t be that bad!"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":249,"question":"I don’t feel very well. I think I’m getting the flu.\r\n“_____”\r\n","options":{"A":" Poor you! That happens to me sometimes.\r\n","B":" Why don’t you go home to bed?\r\n","C":" I’m sorry to hear that but I’m sure he’ll be all right.\r\n","D":" Cheer up! Things can’t be that bad!"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":250,"question":"“I’m cold.”\r\n“I _____ the heating on.”\r\n","options":{"A":" am going to put ","B":" will put\r\n","C":" put ","D":" will be putting"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":251,"question":"“Can I speak to Marco?”\r\n“Hold on. I _____ him.”\r\n","options":{"A":" got ","B":" am going to get\r\n","C":" get ","D":" will get"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":252,"question":"“Coffee or tea?”\r\n“I ____ tea, please.”\r\n","options":{"A":" will have ","B":" have\r\n","C":" am going to have ","D":" had"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":253,"question":"“Has Amy got any plans for the weekend?”\r\n“Yes, she _____ her grandparents.\r\n","options":{"A":" will visit ","B":" visits\r\n","C":" is going to visit ","D":" visited"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":254,"question":"“Alison’s on the phone for you.”\r\n“Can she call back? I ____ a bath.”\r\n","options":{"A":" will have ","B":" am going to have\r\n","C":" have ","D":" having of"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":255,"question":"“I _____ to the supermarket.”\r\n“Oh, ____? I think I _____ with you.”\r\n","options":{"A":" go / are you / am going to come\r\n","B":" will go / will you / will come\r\n","C":" am going to go / are you / will come\r\n","D":" am going / do you / come"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":256,"question":"A: Did you get my fax?\r\nB: No, I didn’t.\r\nA: OK, I _____ it again.\r\n","options":{"A":" send ","B":" will send\r\n","C":" am going to send ","D":" am sending\r\n"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":257,"question":"He’s _____ older than he looks.\r\n","options":{"A":" much ","B":" more ","C":" * ","D":" the"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":258,"question":"Jessica’s as tall _____ her mother.\r\n","options":{"A":" than ","B":" like ","C":" more ","D":" as"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":259,"question":"“What _____ New York like?”\r\n“It’s really exciting!”\r\n","options":{"A":" does ","B":" is ","C":" was ","D":" did"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":260,"question":"Trains in London are more crowded _____ in Paris.\r\n","options":{"A":" that ","B":" as ","C":" than ","D":" like"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":261,"question":"Oxford is one of ___ oldest universities in Europe.\r\n","options":{"A":" the ","B":" * ","C":" much ","D":" more"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":262,"question":"He isn’t as intelligent _____ his sister.\r\n","options":{"A":" like ","B":" as ","C":" than ","D":" nothing"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":263,"question":"This is _____ than I expected.\r\n","options":{"A":" more hard ","B":" hard ","C":" the hardest ","D":" harder"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":264,"question":"Who is the _____ man in the world?\r\n","options":{"A":" rich ","B":" most richest\r\n","C":" richest ","D":" most rich"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":265,"question":"Everything is _____ in my country.\r\n","options":{"A":" more cheaper ","B":" cheaper\r\n","C":" cheap ","D":" cheapest"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":266,"question":"Rome was hotter _____ I expected.\r\n","options":{"A":" than ","B":" that ","C":" nothing ","D":" as"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":267,"question":"My dad’s really ____. He always buys presents for everyone.\r\n","options":{"A":" romantic ","B":" fortunate ","C":" generous ","D":" depressed"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":268,"question":"Before you can get a credit card, you have to provide a lot of _____\r\ndetails.\r\n","options":{"A":" wealth ","B":" person ","C":" happiness ","D":" personal"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":269,"question":"I try to lead a _____ lifestyle - lots of exercises, fruit, and no junk\r\nfood.\r\n","options":{"A":" depressed ","B":" dirty ","C":" healthy ","D":" mess"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":270,"question":"The disco was so _____ that you couldn’t hear yourself speak.\r\n","options":{"A":" noisy ","B":" finance ","C":" windy ","D":" difference"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":271,"question":"After the earthquake, the country needed a lot of _____ equipment\r\nto look after the sick and wounded.\r\n","options":{"A":" depressed ","B":" medical ","C":" personal ","D":" financial"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":272,"question":"She had a car crash, but she was _____ to escape with no injuries at\r\nall.\r\n","options":{"A":" depressed ","B":" romantic ","C":" lucky ","D":" healthy"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":273,"question":"Venice is a very _____ city. A lot of people go there on honeymoon.\r\n","options":{"A":" dirty ","B":" polluted ","C":" wealthy ","D":" romantic"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":274,"question":"Here is the ____ news. Share prices on the Dow Jones Index have\r\nfallen dramatically.\r\n","options":{"A":" cheap ","B":" financial ","C":" depressed ","D":" wealthy"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":275,"question":"After a heart attack, he needed a major surgery, but fortunately the\r\noperation was _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" happy ","B":" different ","C":" successful ","D":" personal"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":276,"question":"I didn’t like that city at all. The streets were so _____ and the air was\r\nso _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" dirty / messy ","B":" dirty / polluted\r\n","C":" personal / noisy ","D":" messy / polluting"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":277,"question":"There’s the boy _____ broke the window.\r\n","options":{"A":" which ","B":" where ","C":" * ","D":" who"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":278,"question":"That’s the palace _____ the King lives.\r\n","options":{"A":" who ","B":" which ","C":" where ","D":" when"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":279,"question":"They are the policemen _____ caught the thief.\r\n","options":{"A":" where ","B":" who ","C":" which ","D":" *"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":280,"question":"He gave him a watch _____ stopped after two days.\r\n","options":{"A":" that ","B":" * ","C":" when ","D":" where"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":281,"question":"The Red Lion is the pub _____ we met for a drink.\r\n","options":{"A":" which ","B":" that ","C":" where ","D":" when"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":282,"question":"Here are the letters _____ arrived this morning.\r\n","options":{"A":" who ","B":" which ","C":" * ","D":" where"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":283,"question":"That’s the house _____ I was born.\r\n","options":{"A":" when ","B":" that ","C":" where ","D":" which"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":284,"question":"Where is the woman _____ ordered the fish.\r\n","options":{"A":" who ","B":" which ","C":" when ","D":" where"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":285,"question":"The hotel _____ we stayed was very comfortable.\r\n","options":{"A":" which ","B":" that ","C":" where ","D":" when"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":286,"question":"I bought the coat _____ was in the shop window.\r\n","options":{"A":" who ","B":" where ","C":" that ","D":" *"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":287,"question":"Are you as tall _____ your brother?\r\n","options":{"A":" like ","B":" as ","C":" than ","D":" more"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":288,"question":"Was Joan’s party better _____ Maria’s?\r\n","options":{"A":" than ","B":" much ","C":" like ","D":" as"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":289,"question":"“Wasn’t that film wonderful!”\r\n“Yes, it was _____.”\r\n","options":{"A":" modern ","B":" wealthy ","C":" brilliant ","D":" depressed"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":290,"question":"“I’m bored with this lesson!”\r\n“I know, I’m really _____ with it, too!”\r\n","options":{"A":" generous ","B":" fed up ","C":" healthy ","D":" happy"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":291,"question":"“Mary’s family is very rich.”\r\n“Well, I knew her uncle was very _____.”\r\n","options":{"A":" finance ","B":" polluted ","C":" wealthy ","D":" windy"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":292,"question":"“Ann’s bedroom’s really untidy again!”\r\n“Is it? I told her it was _____ yesterday, and she promised to clean\r\nit.”\r\n","options":{"A":" clean ","B":" shining ","C":" modern ","D":" messy"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":293,"question":"She’s _____ than her sister.\r\n","options":{"A":" much nicer ","B":" more nicer\r\n","C":" much more nicer ","D":" more nicer"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":294,"question":"He’s _____ boy in the class.\r\n","options":{"A":" the funnier ","B":" funniest\r\n","C":" funnier ","D":" the funniest"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":295,"question":"Barbara’s _____ than Sarah.\r\n","options":{"A":" intelligenter ","B":" much intelligent\r\n","C":" more intelligent ","D":" intelligent\r\n"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":296,"question":"_____ to a rock concert?\r\n","options":{"A":" Were you ever go ","B":" Have you ever been\r\n","C":" Do you ever go ","D":" Have you ever go"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":297,"question":"I _____ the champion last week.\r\n","options":{"A":" saw ","B":" have seen ","C":" see ","D":" seen"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":298,"question":"I love rock and roll. I _____ it all my life.\r\n","options":{"A":" am liking ","B":" like ","C":" liking ","D":" have liked"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":299,"question":"The Flash’s concert _____ fantastic 3 years ago.\r\n","options":{"A":" was ","B":" has been ","C":" have been ","D":" are"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":300,"question":"I _____ all their records since then.\r\n","options":{"A":" bought ","B":" buy ","C":" buyed ","D":" have bought"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":301,"question":"The Flash _____ together for over fifteen years.\r\n","options":{"A":" are ","B":" have been ","C":" are being ","D":" *"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":302,"question":"He’s my sister’s son. He’s my _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" uncle ","B":" nephew ","C":" niece ","D":" bride"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":303,"question":"I run in races. I’m a(n) _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" pilot ","B":" teenager ","C":" athlete ","D":" chef"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":304,"question":"In my job I wear the latest fashions. I’m a(n) _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" actor ","B":" professor ","C":" nurse ","D":" model"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":305,"question":"I serve you drinks on a plane flight. I’m a _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" cousin ","B":" flight attendant\r\n","C":" niece ","D":" child"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":306,"question":"I cook food for a restaurant. I’m a(n) _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" chef ","B":" musician ","C":" uncle ","D":" professor"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":307,"question":"The wedding was wonderful. The _____ looked beautiful, and the\r\n_____ was very handsome.\r\n","options":{"A":" bridegroom / bride ","B":" niece / nephew\r\n","C":" bride / bridegroom ","D":" sir / madam"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":308,"question":"He’s the man _____ Anna loves.\r\n","options":{"A":" which ","B":" * ","C":" this ","D":" when"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":309,"question":"The film star gave a party _____ cost $10.000.\r\n","options":{"A":" * ","B":" who ","C":" which ","D":" where"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":310,"question":"The man ______ you met at the party was a famous film star.\r\n","options":{"A":" who ","B":" when ","C":" where ","D":" which"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":311,"question":"What’s the name of the woman _____ was wearing the gold dress?\r\n","options":{"A":" * ","B":" which ","C":" where ","D":" who"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":312,"question":"You’re reading the book _____ I wanted to read.\r\n","options":{"A":" when ","B":" who ","C":" which ","D":" where"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":313,"question":"There’s someone at the door _____ wants to speak to George.\r\n","options":{"A":" who ","B":" that ","C":" which ","D":" *"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":314,"question":"I don’t like food _____ is very spicy.\r\n","options":{"A":" which ","B":" * ","C":" who ","D":" when"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":315,"question":"That’s the dictionary _____ Bill gave me for my birthday.\r\n","options":{"A":" * ","B":" who ","C":" when ","D":" where"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":316,"question":"Those are old cars _____ only take leaded petrol.\r\n","options":{"A":" who ","B":" when ","C":" * ","D":" which"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":317,"question":"Do you like the people _____ Sarah invited to her party?\r\n","options":{"A":" which ","B":" who ","C":" where ","D":" when"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":318,"question":"I called Tom at 10.00 in the morning, but he was _____ in bed.\r\n","options":{"A":" of course ","B":" still ","C":" only ","D":" especially"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":319,"question":"It’s our anniversary today. We’ve been _____ for fifteen years.\r\n","options":{"A":" at last ","B":" exactly ","C":" together ","D":" nearly"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":320,"question":"Kate is very fussy about food. She _____ eats pasta and crisps.\r\n","options":{"A":" only ","B":" hard ","C":" exactly ","D":" too"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":321,"question":"She was very ill and _____ died, but fortunately, she got better.\r\n","options":{"A":" carefully ","B":" nearly ","C":" too ","D":" usually"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":322,"question":"“I hate ironing.”\r\n“Me, _____. It’s so boring.”\r\n","options":{"A":" just ","B":" at last ","C":" slowly ","D":" too"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":323,"question":"I like all Russian novelists, _____ Tolstoy.\r\n","options":{"A":" usually ","B":" especially ","C":" together ","D":" only"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":324,"question":"I met her on December 23, _____ before Christmas.\r\n","options":{"A":" too ","B":" slowly ","C":" just ","D":" still"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":325,"question":"_____ I have finished this exercise. Thank goodness! It was so boring.\r\n","options":{"A":" Together ","B":" At last ","C":" Exactly ","D":" Just"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":326,"question":"Sarah’s English is getting better. She _____ a lot of English since she\r\n_____ here.\r\n","options":{"A":" learnt / has come ","B":" has learnt / has come\r\n","C":" has learnt / came ","D":" learnt / came"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":327,"question":"Mike and Jack _____ here five months ago. They _____ in this city\r\nfor five months.\r\n","options":{"A":" came / have been ","B":" have come / have been\r\n","C":" come / were ","D":" has come / has been"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":328,"question":"David can go to bed now. He _____ his homework.\r\n","options":{"A":" finish ","B":" has finished\r\n","C":" finishes ","D":" finished"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":329,"question":"Alison _____ in Chicago, but she would like to go there one day.\r\n","options":{"A":" was ","B":" has been\r\n","C":" wasn’t ","D":" has never been"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":330,"question":"Peter _____ his work 3 hours ago.\r\n","options":{"A":" has finished ","B":" will finish\r\n","C":" finished ","D":" finish\r\nDennis Heal __(36)__ a politician. He __(37)__ to Oxford University\r\nin 1975, and in 1982 he __(38)__ a Member of Parliament. He\r\n__(39)__ an MP since then. He __(40)__ Defense Minister from 1989-95 He __(41)__ three books, including his autobiography “The Time\r\nof my Life”, and a spy story called “The Time to Run”. He is married\r\nto the artist Edna Heal, and they have two children. They __(42)__\r\nin Oxford for 10 years, then they __(43)__ to London in 1995. They\r\nnow __(44)__ in a house in Queen Square in central London."},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":331,"question":"","options":{"A":" was ","B":" is ","C":" is being ","D":" has been"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":332,"question":"","options":{"A":" go ","B":" has gone ","C":" went ","D":" goes"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":333,"question":"","options":{"A":" became ","B":" become ","C":" becomes ","D":" has become"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":334,"question":"","options":{"A":" was ","B":" is being ","C":" is ","D":" has been"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":335,"question":"","options":{"A":" was ","B":" is ","C":" has been ","D":" were"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":336,"question":"","options":{"A":" has written ","B":" wrote ","C":" write ","D":" writes"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":337,"question":"","options":{"A":" lives ","B":" has lived ","C":" have lived ","D":" live"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":338,"question":"","options":{"A":" move ","B":" moved ","C":" is moving ","D":" has moved"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":339,"question":"","options":{"A":" lives ","B":" have lived ","C":" lived ","D":" live"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":340,"question":"I haven’t seen Keith _____ a while.\r\n","options":{"A":" since ","B":" * ","C":" for ","D":" in"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":341,"question":"He and his wife have lived next to me _____ their son, Tom, was\r\nborn.\r\n","options":{"A":" for ","B":" when ","C":" since ","D":" *"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":342,"question":"I have known them _____ many years.\r\n","options":{"A":" * ","B":" for ","C":" on ","D":" since"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":343,"question":"Anna has had a bad cold _____ the last few days.\r\n","options":{"A":" for ","B":" after ","C":" since ","D":" in"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":344,"question":"I have written a letter _____ breakfast.\r\n","options":{"A":" * ","B":" before ","C":" for ","D":" since"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":345,"question":"I’m looking after Tom today. He’s been at my house _____ 8.00 this\r\nmorning.\r\n","options":{"A":" at ","B":" for ","C":" since ","D":" from\r\n"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":346,"question":"“Why have you got so much food?”\r\n“Because I _____ a meal for two people.”\r\n","options":{"A":" cook ","B":" am going to cook\r\n","C":" will cook ","D":" had cook"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":347,"question":"“Jane told me you have a place at university.”\r\n“That’s right. I _____ math at St. Andrews in Scotland.”\r\n","options":{"A":" studied ","B":" will study\r\n","C":" study ","D":" am going to study"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":348,"question":"“My car isn’t working.”\r\n“Ask Joe to look at it. He _____ you.”\r\n","options":{"A":" will help ","B":" helps\r\n","C":" is going to help ","D":" helped"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":349,"question":"“I passed my driving test!”\r\n“That’s great! I _____ some champagne to celebrate!”\r\n","options":{"A":" am going to buy ","B":" will buy\r\n","C":" bought ","D":" am buying"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":350,"question":"“Why have you got your old clothes on?”\r\n“Because I _____ the grass.’\r\n","options":{"A":" had cut ","B":" cutted\r\n","C":" am going to cut ","D":" cut"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":351,"question":"He’s worked there _____ many years, _____ 1988, I believe.\r\n","options":{"A":" since / ever ","B":" for / ever\r\n","C":" for / since ","D":" ever / never"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":352,"question":"I have _____ loved anyone as much as I love you.\r\n","options":{"A":" never ","B":" since ","C":" for ","D":" ever"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":353,"question":"We’ve known Paul _____ two years. Have you _____ met him?\r\n","options":{"A":" since / for ","B":" since / ever ","C":" for / ever ","D":" never / ever"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":354,"question":"I’ve known him _____ we went to school together, but I’ve _____\r\nmet his parents.\r\n","options":{"A":" ever / ever ","B":" for / never ","C":" since / for ","D":" since / never"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":355,"question":"Your hair’s too long. I think you _____ get it cut.\r\n","options":{"A":" have to ","B":" should ","C":" * ","D":" will"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":356,"question":"Your clothes smell, and you’ve got a cough. You _____ smoke.\r\n","options":{"A":" don’t have to ","B":" should\r\n","C":" shouldn’t ","D":" have to"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":357,"question":"I’m going to bed. I _____ be up early tomorrow.\r\n","options":{"A":" should ","B":" shouldn’t\r\n","C":" don’t have to ","D":" have to"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":358,"question":"I’d like to meet your boyfriend. You _____ invite him round.\r\n","options":{"A":" must ","B":" have to ","C":" would ","D":" don’t have to\r\n14 I _____ tell my parents where I am, then they don’t worry.\r\n"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":359,"question":"You _____ come with me if you don’t want to. I’ll go on my own.\r\n","options":{"A":" don’t have to ","B":" must\r\n","C":" should ","D":" shouldn’t"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":360,"question":"Our train leaves in two minutes! We _____ hurry.\r\n","options":{"A":" would ","B":" have to\r\n","C":" must ","D":" don’t have to"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":361,"question":"If you need some help with your homework, you _____ go to the\r\nlibrary.\r\n","options":{"A":" should ","B":" mustn’t ","C":" have to ","D":" shouldn’t"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":362,"question":"If you’ve got a ticket, you _____ queue. You can go straight in.”\r\n","options":{"A":" shouldn’t ","B":" don’t have to\r\n","C":" have to ","D":" should"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":363,"question":"You _____ tell lies. It’s wrong.\r\n","options":{"A":" don’t have to ","B":" should\r\n","C":" have to ","D":" shouldn’t"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":364,"question":"Geoff works too much. I think he _____ take it easy.\r\n","options":{"A":" must ","B":" have to\r\n","C":" should ","D":" don’t have to"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":365,"question":"My bedroom is a real mess. I _____ clean it.\r\n","options":{"A":" have to ","B":" must\r\n","C":" don’t have to ","D":" should"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":366,"question":"There’s a wonderful new restaurant opened in town. You _____ go\r\nthere.\r\n","options":{"A":" shouldn’t ","B":" must\r\n","C":" don’t have to ","D":" should"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":367,"question":"You can borrow my tennis racquet, but you _____ keep it very well.\r\nIt was very expensive.\r\n","options":{"A":" don’t have to ","B":" should\r\n","C":" must ","D":" have to"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":368,"question":"It’s my mother’s birthday tomorrow. I _____ buy her a present.\r\n","options":{"A":" must ","B":" have to\r\n","C":" shouldn’t ","D":" don’t have to"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":369,"question":"Joanna Trollope _____ a lot of books. She _____ her first in 1980.\r\n","options":{"A":" wrote / wrote ","B":" has written / wrote\r\n","C":" had written / wrote ","D":" wrote / had written"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":370,"question":"I _____ in London for eight years, and I don’t want to move.\r\n","options":{"A":" live ","B":" lived ","C":" had lived ","D":" have lived"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":371,"question":"What is the weather _____ in January?\r\n","options":{"A":" likes ","B":" like ","C":" liked ","D":" don’t like\r\nJohn Frantz is American. He has a wonderful lifestyle and he wants\r\n__(28)__ it with an English girl. He enjoys __(29)__ on exotic holidays,\r\nbut he wouldn’t like __(30)__ outside the United States. He hopes\r\n__(31)__ an English wife through the English Rose dating agency.\r\nHe’d like __(32)__ someone who likes __(33)__."},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":372,"question":"","options":{"A":" sharing ","B":" share ","C":" shared ","D":" to share"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":373,"question":"","options":{"A":" to go ","B":" went ","C":" going ","D":" to going"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":374,"question":"","options":{"A":" living ","B":" to live ","C":" live ","D":" lives"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":375,"question":"","options":{"A":" to find ","B":" found ","C":" finding ","D":" to be founded"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":376,"question":"","options":{"A":" meets ","B":" to met ","C":" meeting ","D":" to meet"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":377,"question":"","options":{"A":" traveling ","B":" traveled ","C":" travel ","D":" to traveling"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":378,"question":"You _____ have a driving license if you want to drive a car.\r\n","options":{"A":" should ","B":" have to ","C":" have ","D":" had to"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":379,"question":"I don’t think people _____ get married until they’re 21.\r\n","options":{"A":" have to ","B":" would ","C":" should ","D":" are"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":380,"question":"They liked the hotel because they _____ do any cooking.\r\n","options":{"A":" have to ","B":" had to ","C":" should ","D":" didn’t have to"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":381,"question":"I _____ swim when I was three.\r\n","options":{"A":" could ","B":" can ","C":" have to ","D":" must"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":382,"question":"She _____ work on Monday. It’s her day off.\r\n","options":{"A":" must ","B":" doesn’t have to\r\n","C":" have to ","D":" shouldn’t"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":383,"question":"You _____ sit so close to the TV. It’s bad for your eyes.\r\n","options":{"A":" don’t have to ","B":" have to\r\n","C":" shouldn’t ","D":" can"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":384,"question":"You _____ do the washing-up. I’ve got a washing machine.\r\n","options":{"A":" should ","B":" have to ","C":" mustn’t ","D":" don’t have to"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":385,"question":"“I’m working 16 hours a day.”\r\n“I think you _____ talk to your boss.”\r\n","options":{"A":" have to ","B":" can ","C":" mustn’t ","D":" should"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":386,"question":"“I can’t sleep.”\r\n“You _____ drink coffee at night.”\r\n","options":{"A":" must ","B":" shouldn’t ","C":" don’t have to ","D":" have"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":387,"question":"“My friend is getting married.”\r\n“I _____ go to the wedding.”\r\n","options":{"A":" think you should ","B":" think you have to\r\n","C":" think you can ","D":" think you may"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":388,"question":"“I’ve had a terrible toothache for weeks.”\r\n“You _____ go to the dentist.”\r\n","options":{"A":" have to ","B":" would ","C":" shouldn’t ","D":" should"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":389,"question":"Anne was upset because she didn’t _____ in the race. She really\r\nwanted to win.\r\n","options":{"A":" come last ","B":" go up ","C":" come first ","D":" turn out"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":390,"question":"We always _____ for our holidays.\r\n","options":{"A":" go abroad ","B":" go off ","C":" go on ","D":" go away"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":391,"question":"I’m _____. There’s nothing to do.\r\n","options":{"A":" annoyed ","B":" interested ","C":" kind ","D":" fed up"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":392,"question":"If you want to do well in life you _____ believe in yourself.\r\n","options":{"A":" can ","B":" don’t have to\r\n","C":" have to ","D":" should"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":393,"question":"If you want to keep fit, you _____ do some sport.\r\n","options":{"A":" shouldn’t ","B":" have to ","C":" should ","D":" don’t have to"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":394,"question":"If you want to learn English, you _____ speak your language in English\r\nlessons.\r\n","options":{"A":" should ","B":" don’t have to\r\n","C":" must ","D":" shouldn’t\r\n"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":395,"question":"I will have a bath _____ I go to bed.\r\n","options":{"A":" when ","B":" if ","C":" before ","D":" until"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":396,"question":"I’m coming to London tomorrow. I’ll ring you _____ I arrive.\r\n","options":{"A":" before ","B":" when ","C":" until ","D":" if"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":397,"question":"_____ it is a nice day tomorrow, we can go swimming.\r\n","options":{"A":" If ","B":" Until ","C":" When ","D":" Before"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":398,"question":"Wait here _____ I get back.\r\n","options":{"A":" until ","B":" before ","C":" as soon as ","D":" when"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":399,"question":"_____ you have any problem, just ask for help.\r\n","options":{"A":" When ","B":" After ","C":" Before ","D":" Until"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":400,"question":"I want to get home _____ Jim comes back.\r\n","options":{"A":" if ","B":" before ","C":" until ","D":" when"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":401,"question":"I’m going to have driving lessons _____ I pass my test.\r\n","options":{"A":" before ","B":" when ","C":" if ","D":" until"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":402,"question":"Give me your address _____ you go home.\r\n","options":{"A":" if ","B":" before ","C":" as soon as ","D":" until"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":403,"question":"Bye! I _____ you when I _____ home.\r\n","options":{"A":" phoned / get ","B":" will phone / will get\r\n","C":" phone / get ","D":" will phone / get"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":404,"question":"I’m going to bed when this TV program _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" ended ","B":" will end\r\n","C":" is going to end ","D":" ends"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":405,"question":"I’m sorry you are leaving. I _____ when you _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" am glad / you are back ","B":" glad / will be back\r\n","C":" will be glad / are back ","D":" am glad / will be back"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":406,"question":"“Give me your phone number.”\r\n“Sure. I _____ it to you before I _____.”\r\n","options":{"A":" will give / go ","B":" give / will go\r\n","C":" will give / will go ","D":" am going to give / go"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":407,"question":"What’s _____ TV tonight?\r\n","options":{"A":" at ","B":" in ","C":" on ","D":" with"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":408,"question":"I often go abroad _____ business.\r\n","options":{"A":" to ","B":" by ","C":" for ","D":" on"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":409,"question":"Do you come to school _____ bus?\r\n","options":{"A":" on ","B":" by ","C":" at ","D":" in"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":410,"question":"I’m very busy _____ the moment.\r\n","options":{"A":" in ","B":" on ","C":" by ","D":" at"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":411,"question":"I can’t understand the instructions. They’re _____ Chinese.\r\n","options":{"A":" by ","B":" at ","C":" in ","D":" for"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":412,"question":"“Romeo and Juliet” is a play _____ William Shakespeare.\r\n","options":{"A":" for ","B":" by ","C":" with ","D":" on"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":413,"question":"“Is Mr. James _____ work this week?”\r\n“No. He’s _____ holiday.”\r\n","options":{"A":" on / in ","B":" at / in ","C":" in / for ","D":" at / on"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":414,"question":"I hate being late. I like to arrive _____ time.\r\n","options":{"A":" by ","B":" on ","C":" at ","D":" for"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":415,"question":"I spoke to her _____ the phone last week.\r\n","options":{"A":" at ","B":" like ","C":" on ","D":" by"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":416,"question":"I read an interesting article _____ the paper this morning.\r\n","options":{"A":" in ","B":" on ","C":" at ","D":" for"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":417,"question":"“Can I ask you something?”\r\n“Not now. _____ a moment.”\r\n","options":{"A":" At ","B":" For ","C":" On ","D":" In"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":418,"question":"“ Here’s a birthday present _____ you.”\r\n“Oh, thank you!”\r\n","options":{"A":" by ","B":" in ","C":" for ","D":" at"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":419,"question":"“Why did you open my letter?”\r\n“I’m sorry. I did it _____ mistake.”\r\n","options":{"A":" with ","B":" at ","C":" by ","D":" on"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":420,"question":"I arrived _____ England last month.\r\n","options":{"A":" at ","B":" to ","C":" in ","D":" for"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":421,"question":"I live _____ the third floor.\r\n","options":{"A":" at ","B":" on ","C":" by ","D":" in"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":422,"question":"I met my classmates _____ the party.\r\n","options":{"A":" in ","B":" for ","C":" on ","D":" at"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":423,"question":"“Why does Jane look so happy?”\r\n“Because she’s _____ love.”\r\n","options":{"A":" at ","B":" on ","C":" in ","D":" by"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":424,"question":"Let’s go _____ a walk.\r\n","options":{"A":" on ","B":" to ","C":" in ","D":" for"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":425,"question":"We arrived _____ the station five minutes late.\r\n","options":{"A":" to ","B":" at ","C":" for ","D":" on"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":426,"question":"The doctor will be ready in ten minutes. Take a seat while you _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" are wait ","B":" will wait ","C":" are waiting ","D":" wait"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":427,"question":"I’m going out before the shops _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" will shut ","B":" shuts ","C":" are shutting ","D":" shut"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":428,"question":"I _____ by the phone until _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" wait / you ring ","B":" will wait / you will ring\r\n","C":" wait / you will ring ","D":" will wait / you ring"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":429,"question":"You must phone me as soon as _____ your exam results.\r\n","options":{"A":" you get ","B":" you will get\r\n","C":" you got ","D":" you are going to get"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":430,"question":"I hope to see you while I _____ in London.\r\n","options":{"A":" am ","B":" will be\r\n","C":" am going to be ","D":" was"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":431,"question":"_____ I win a lot of money, I’ll buy you a Ferrari.\r\n","options":{"A":" When ","B":" If ","C":" Until ","D":" As long as"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":432,"question":"Please turn out the lights _____ you go to bed.\r\n","options":{"A":" after ","B":" as soon as ","C":" while ","D":" before"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":433,"question":"I like to relax _____ I’m on holiday.\r\n","options":{"A":" while ","B":" before ","C":" if ","D":" as soon as"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":434,"question":"_____ you are the first person up in the morning, make me a cup of\r\ncoffee.\r\n","options":{"A":" When ","B":" If ","C":" As soon as ","D":" While"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":435,"question":"I’m going to keep asking you to marry me _____ you say “Yes”.\r\n","options":{"A":" while ","B":" when ","C":" until ","D":" before"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":436,"question":"We can go _____ you’re ready.\r\n","options":{"A":" if ","B":" after ","C":" before ","D":" while"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":437,"question":"_____ I’m having my hair cut, you can do the shopping.\r\n","options":{"A":" When ","B":" While ","C":" As soon as ","D":" If"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":438,"question":"Stop at a petrol station _____ we run out of the petrol.\r\n","options":{"A":" before ","B":" until ","C":" after ","D":" when"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":439,"question":"_____ you’ve read the newspaper, can I have it?\r\n","options":{"A":" Until ","B":" After ","C":" Before ","D":" *"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":440,"question":"I am so worried about James, _____ you hear any news, phone me.\r\n","options":{"A":" while ","B":" until ","C":" as soon as ","D":" before"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":441,"question":"_____ we discover life on another planet, will it be intelligent?\r\n","options":{"A":" As soon as ","B":" When ","C":" Until ","D":" If"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":442,"question":"I’ll have a bath _____ I go to work.\r\n","options":{"A":" after ","B":" as soon as ","C":" before ","D":" while"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":443,"question":"_____ the lesson ends, I’ll go home.\r\n","options":{"A":" Before ","B":" Until ","C":" If ","D":" As soon as"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":444,"question":"I’ll study English _____ I speak it perfectly.\r\n","options":{"A":" if ","B":" after ","C":" until ","D":" when\r\n"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":445,"question":"He agreed _____ the job as soon as possible.\r\n","options":{"A":" start ","B":" starting ","C":" to start ","D":" starts"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":446,"question":"I stopped _____ my book and went to bed.\r\n","options":{"A":" to read ","B":" read ","C":" will read ","D":" reading"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":447,"question":"My teachers always expected me _____ well in exams.\r\n","options":{"A":" did ","B":" doing ","C":" do ","D":" to do"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":448,"question":"Let me _____ for the meal. You paid last time.\r\n","options":{"A":" pay ","B":" to pay ","C":" paid ","D":" paying"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":449,"question":"The dentist told me _____ more careful when I brush my teeth.\r\n","options":{"A":" will be ","B":" being ","C":" to be ","D":" be"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":450,"question":"I asked Monica _____ some stamps.\r\n","options":{"A":" buys ","B":" buying ","C":" to buy ","D":" buy"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":451,"question":"I never liked _____ to church when I was a child.\r\n","options":{"A":" going ","B":" to do ","C":" went ","D":" go"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":452,"question":"Have you finished _____ that letter yet?\r\n","options":{"A":" to write ","B":" writing ","C":" writes ","D":" write"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":453,"question":"You can’t _____ your car outside the hospital.\r\n","options":{"A":" parks ","B":" to park ","C":" park ","D":" parking"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":454,"question":"David always enjoyed _____ football at school.\r\n","options":{"A":" to be played ","B":" playing ","C":" to play ","D":" play"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":455,"question":"The TV program was so _____ that I felt asleep.\r\n","options":{"A":" tired ","B":" surprising ","C":" annoyed ","D":" boring"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":456,"question":"Children can’t get to sleep on Christmas Eve.\r\nThey’re too _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" bored ","B":" excited ","C":" frightened ","D":" worrying"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":457,"question":"“Hi, Mum!”\r\n“Carol! Thank goodness you rang! Where have you been? We’ve\r\nbeen so _____ about you.”\r\n","options":{"A":" interested ","B":" annoying ","C":" worried ","D":" frightening"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":458,"question":"A: Hello, darling. I’ve got a present for you.\r\nB: For me?\r\nA: Don’t look so _____. I often buy you presents.\r\nB: But it isn’t my birthday!\r\n","options":{"A":" bored ","B":" exciting ","C":" tiring ","D":" surprised"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":459,"question":"The art exhibition was very _____. I loved it.\r\n","options":{"A":" surprised ","B":" boring ","C":" interesting ","D":" excited"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":460,"question":"My feet are killing me! I find going round art galleries and museums\r\nvery _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" tiring ","B":" worrying ","C":" boring ","D":" frightening"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":461,"question":"Some people don’t go out at night because they’re _____ that\r\nsomeone will rob them.\r\n","options":{"A":" worried ","B":" annoying ","C":" surprised ","D":" frightened"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":462,"question":"Our financial situation is very _____. We spend more and more, but\r\nwe’re earning less and less.\r\n","options":{"A":" worrying ","B":" exciting ","C":" frightened ","D":" interesting"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":463,"question":"A: You are yawning. Are you listening to what I am saying?”\r\nB: I am! I’m really _____. I want to know what happened. It’s just\r\nthat I feel very _____. I went to bed very late last night.\r\n","options":{"A":" surprised / tiring ","B":" excited / worrying\r\n","C":" interested / tired ","D":" frightened / bored"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":464,"question":"“I’m going on a three-month holiday to the Far East.”\r\n“How _____! Lucky you!”\r\n","options":{"A":" frightening ","B":" interested ","C":" boring ","D":" exciting"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":465,"question":"“Was your father _____ when you told him your exam results?”\r\n“He was furious.”\r\n","options":{"A":" annoyed ","B":" worrying ","C":" frightened ","D":" tired"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":466,"question":"“What _____ to do?”\r\n“I’m looking for my contact lens. Can you see it?”\r\n","options":{"A":" do you try ","B":" will you try\r\n","C":" are you trying ","D":" did you try"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":467,"question":"“I’ll help you. What _____ me to do?”\r\n“Could you do the washing-up while I am doing the cooking?”\r\n","options":{"A":" you want ","B":" are you wanting\r\n","C":" did you want ","D":" do you want"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":468,"question":"“What _____ you to do?”\r\n“She (the doctor) told me to stay in bed for a few days.”\r\n","options":{"A":" will she tell ","B":" did she tell\r\n","C":" is she going to tell ","D":" does she tell"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":469,"question":"“My mother was so helpful while she was staying with us”\r\n“What _____ to do?”\r\n","options":{"A":" did she help you ","B":" does she help you\r\n","C":" will she help you ","D":" was she helping you"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":470,"question":"“What _____ to do tonight?”\r\n“What about going out for a meal?”\r\n","options":{"A":" do you like ","B":" would you like\r\n","C":" are liking ","D":" will you like"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":471,"question":"“What _____ to do after university?”\r\n“I’d like to get a job in publishing.”\r\n","options":{"A":" do you hope ","B":" will you hope\r\n","C":" are you going to hope ","D":" are you hope"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":472,"question":"My family is trying _____ where to go on holiday.\r\n","options":{"A":" decided ","B":" decide ","C":" to decide ","D":" deciding"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":473,"question":"I’d like _____ somewhere different for a change.\r\n","options":{"A":" went ","B":" to go ","C":" go ","D":" going"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":474,"question":"I enjoy _____ places I’ve never been to before.\r\n","options":{"A":" visiting ","B":" to visit ","C":" visits ","D":" visit"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":475,"question":"But my children hate _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" sightsee ","B":" to sightsee ","C":" sightseeing ","D":"will sightsee"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":476,"question":"They prefer _____ in a swimming pool all day.\r\n","options":{"A":" playing ","B":" plays ","C":" to play ","D":" to playing"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":477,"question":"They refuse _____ out on trips if it’s too hot.\r\n","options":{"A":" to going ","B":" to go ","C":" going ","D":" go"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":478,"question":"Last year we managed _____ a holiday that suited everyone.\r\n","options":{"A":" found ","B":" to find ","C":" find ","D":" finding"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":479,"question":"We decided _____ a house with a swimming pool.\r\n","options":{"A":" renting ","B":" rent ","C":" to renting ","D":" to rent"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":480,"question":"A woman from a travel agency helped us _____ a nice house.\r\n","options":{"A":" to choose ","B":" choosing ","C":" chooses ","D":" too choose"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":481,"question":"When we arrived, the people next door invited us _____ a drink\r\nwith them.\r\n","options":{"A":" have ","B":" to have ","C":" to had ","D":" having"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":482,"question":"We began _____ about next year’s holiday two months ago.\r\n","options":{"A":" talked ","B":" talking ","C":" talks ","D":" talk"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":483,"question":"Everyone hopes ____ themselves on holiday but it isn’t always easy.\r\n","options":{"A":" enjoy ","B":" to enjoy ","C":" be enjoyed ","D":" enjoying"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":484,"question":"My wife and I are starting _____ we should stay at home.\r\n","options":{"A":" thinking ","B":" think ","C":" to think ","D":" thought"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":485,"question":"I went to the shops _____ some shoes.\r\n","options":{"A":" buy ","B":" for to buy ","C":" to buy ","D":" for buy"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":486,"question":"Do you enjoy _____?\r\n","options":{"A":" dance ","B":" dancing ","C":" danced ","D":" to dance"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":487,"question":"When I was young, I _____ ice-skating.\r\n","options":{"A":" went to ","B":" go ","C":" used to go ","D":" going"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":488,"question":"He told me he loved me. I didn’t know what _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" to say ","B":" say ","C":" will I say ","D":" saying"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":489,"question":"Their house is _____ mess! I don’t know how they live in it.\r\n","options":{"A":" so ","B":" such an ","C":" so many ","D":" such a"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":490,"question":"There were _____ people at the party! There was nowhere to dance.\r\n","options":{"A":" such a ","B":" so many ","C":" so much ","D":" such"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":491,"question":"I’m _____ hungry. I could eat a horse.\r\n","options":{"A":" so ","B":" such a ","C":" such ","D":" so much"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":492,"question":"Jane and Pete are _____ nice people! But I can’t stand their kids.\r\n","options":{"A":" so many ","B":" so ","C":" such a ","D":" such"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":493,"question":"I’ve spent _____ money this week! I don’t know where it’s all gone.\r\n","options":{"A":" such ","B":" so many ","C":" so much ","D":" so"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":494,"question":"A present! For me? You’re _____ kind!\r\n","options":{"A":" such ","B":" so many ","C":" so ","D":" such a\r\n\r\nConcorde, the world’s fastest passenger plane, __(1)__ by France\r\nand Britain together. In the 1950s, both countries dreamed of having\r\na supersonic plane, and the project __(2)__ in 1962. £1.5 billion\r\n__(3)__ on developing the Concorde, and it __(4)__ for over 5.000\r\nhours, which makes it the most tested plane in history. The first\r\npassenger plane __(5)__ by British Airways and Air France in 1976.\r\nThe Concorde holds many world records, including the fastest\r\ncrossing of the Atlantic Ocean from New York to London, which\r\n__(6)__ in 2 hours 45 seconds! Flying at twice the speed of sound\r\nmeans that flying time __(7)__ by half, which is why the Concorde\r\nflight between London and New York __(8)__ a lot by business people\r\nand film stars - you can leave Britain at 10.30 and arrive in New York\r\nan hour earlier! Twenty planes __(9)__ up to the present day. But\r\nthere are no plans to build any more. Each plane __(10)__ at a cost\r\nof £55 million, which makes them very expensive!"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":495,"question":"","options":{"A":" developed ","B":" have been developed\r\n","C":" was developed ","D":" develops"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":496,"question":"","options":{"A":" was started ","B":" starts\r\n","C":" have been started ","D":" started"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":497,"question":"","options":{"A":" spend ","B":" was spent\r\n","C":" have been spent ","D":" spent"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":498,"question":"","options":{"A":" has tested ","B":" tested\r\n","C":" have been tested ","D":" was tested"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":499,"question":"","options":{"A":" introduce ","B":" has been introduced\r\n","C":" introduces ","D":" was introduced"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":500,"question":"","options":{"A":" have been achieved ","B":" was achieved\r\n","C":" will achieve ","D":" achieved"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":501,"question":"","options":{"A":" was reduced ","B":" has reduced\r\n","C":" is reduced ","D":" will be reduced"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":502,"question":"","options":{"A":" had been used ","B":" uses\r\n","C":" used ","D":" is used"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":503,"question":"","options":{"A":" were built ","B":" are built\r\n","C":" have been built ","D":" build"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":504,"question":"","options":{"A":" is being produced ","B":" is produced\r\n","C":" was produced ","D":" has been produced"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":505,"question":"Where _____ these shoes made?\r\n","options":{"A":" was ","B":" were ","C":" did ","D":" is"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":506,"question":"I was given this watch _____ my aunt.\r\n","options":{"A":" to ","B":" from ","C":" * ","D":" by"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":507,"question":"Someone _____ my bag!\r\n","options":{"A":" was stolen ","B":" has been stolen\r\n","C":" has stolen ","D":" is stolen"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":508,"question":"A newsagent _____ stamps.\r\n","options":{"A":" sells ","B":" is sold ","C":" was sold ","D":" sell"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":509,"question":"A British policeman _____ guns.\r\n","options":{"A":" aren’t carried ","B":" don’t carry\r\n","C":" hasn’t been carried ","D":" doesn’t carry"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":510,"question":"All the apple juice _____ by nine o’clock.\r\n","options":{"A":" drunk ","B":" was drunk ","C":" was drank ","D":" drink"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":511,"question":"Have all the sandwiches _____?\r\n","options":{"A":" been eaten ","B":" eaten ","C":" was ate ","D":" ate"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":512,"question":"_____ hello to your parents from me when you see them.\r\n","options":{"A":" Tell ","B":" Say ","C":" Give ","D":" Keep"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":513,"question":"I was late for work because I _____ the bus.\r\n","options":{"A":" carried ","B":" lost ","C":" waited for ","D":" missed"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":514,"question":"This is my grandfather’s watch. He _____ it every day until he died.\r\n","options":{"A":" gave ","B":" carried ","C":" wore ","D":" kept"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":515,"question":"I _____ just _____ a good idea. Let’s eat out tonight.\r\n","options":{"A":" have / kept ","B":" have / had ","C":" am / told ","D":" had / carried"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":516,"question":"My uncle _____ £500 on the stock exchange.\r\n","options":{"A":" keeps ","B":" grows ","C":" carries ","D":" earns"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":517,"question":"We _____ a complaint to the manager because our meal was so\r\nbad.\r\n","options":{"A":" made ","B":" said ","C":" gave ","D":" told"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":518,"question":"Rolls Royce cars _____ in England.\r\n","options":{"A":" were made ","B":" is made ","C":" makes ","D":" are made"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":519,"question":"They _____ rice in China.\r\n","options":{"A":" are grown ","B":" grow\r\n","C":" have been grown ","D":" grows"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":520,"question":"The telephone _____ by Bell in 1876.\r\n","options":{"A":" has invented ","B":" is invented\r\n","C":" was invented ","D":" invented"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":521,"question":"Thieves _____ two pictures from the museum last night.\r\n","options":{"A":" have stolen ","B":" stole ","C":" was stolen ","D":" had stolen"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":522,"question":"They _____ the picture for £3.000.\r\n","options":{"A":" has sold ","B":" are sold ","C":" sold ","D":" sell"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":523,"question":"Three new factories _____ this year.\r\n","options":{"A":" built ","B":" were built\r\n","C":" have been built ","D":" has built"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":524,"question":"10.000 cars _____ next year.\r\n","options":{"A":" will produce ","B":" produced\r\n","C":" are produced ","D":" will be produced"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":525,"question":"The television _____ by Bell.\r\n","options":{"A":" was invented ","B":" is invented\r\n","C":" wasn’t invented ","D":" invented"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":526,"question":"_____ they _____ many cars last year?\r\n","options":{"A":" Have / made ","B":" Did / make\r\n","C":" Will / make ","D":" Been / made\r\nNylon __(33)__ in the early 1930s by an American chemist, Julian Hill.\r\nOther scientists __(34)__ with his invention, and finally on 27 October,\r\n1938 nylon __(35)__ to the world. It was cheap and strong and\r\nimmediately __(36)__ successful, especially in the making of women’s\r\nstockings.\r\nDuring the Second World War, the best present for many women was\r\na pair of nylon stockings, but more importantly, nylon __(37)__ to\r\nmake parachutes and tires.\r\nToday, nylon __(38)__ in many things: carpets, ropes, seat belts,\r\nfurniture, computers, and even spare parts for the human body. It\r\n__(39)__ an important part in our lives for over 50 years. Next year\r\nabout 36 million tons of it __(40)__."},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":527,"question":"","options":{"A":" invented ","B":" has been invented\r\n","C":" is invented ","D":" was invented"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":528,"question":"","options":{"A":" has worked ","B":" worked\r\n","C":" were working","D":" have been working"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":529,"question":"","options":{"A":" was introduced ","B":" introduces\r\n","C":" has introduced ","D":" introduced"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":530,"question":"","options":{"A":" have become","B":" became\r\n","C":" is became ","D":" becomes"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":531,"question":"","options":{"A":" has been used ","B":" used\r\n","C":" was used ","D":" was been used"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":532,"question":"","options":{"A":" found ","B":" founded\r\n","C":" has founded ","D":" is found"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":533,"question":"","options":{"A":" played ","B":" has played ","C":" is playing ","D":" plays"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":534,"question":"","options":{"A":" is manufactured ","B":" will be manufactured\r\n","C":" manufactured ","D":" is going to manufacture"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":535,"question":"English _____ all over the world.\r\n","options":{"A":" speaks ","B":" is spoken\r\n","C":" was spoken ","D":" has been spoken"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":536,"question":"The animals _____ by a loud noise.\r\n","options":{"A":" frightened ","B":" were frightening\r\n","C":" has been frightened ","D":" were frightened"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":537,"question":"My children _____ with their homework.\r\n","options":{"A":" helped ","B":" help ","C":" are helping ","D":" aren’t helped"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":538,"question":"How many times _____ playing football?\r\n","options":{"A":" have you been hurt ","B":" did you hurt\r\n","C":" were you hurted ","D":" are you hurt"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":539,"question":"The thieves _____ by anyone.\r\n","options":{"A":" saw ","B":" have been seen\r\n","C":" weren’t seen ","D":" didn’t seen"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":540,"question":"Coffee _____ in England.\r\n","options":{"A":" grows ","B":" isn’t grown\r\n","C":" grew ","D":" have been grown"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":541,"question":"____ last night?\r\n","options":{"A":" Have the plants been watered\r\n","B":" Did the plants water\r\n","C":" Were the plants watered\r\n","D":" Are they watered"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":542,"question":"Driving should _____ in city centers.\r\n","options":{"A":" ban ","B":" be banned ","C":" banned ","D":" being ban"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":543,"question":"America _____ by Christopher Columbus.\r\n","options":{"A":" has discovered ","B":" have discovered\r\n","C":" had been discovered ","D":" was discovered"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":544,"question":"The house is going _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" to knock down ","B":" to be knocked down\r\n","C":" to been knocked down ","D":" knocking down\r\n"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":545,"question":"Don’t wait for me. I _____ late. It depends on the traffic.\r\n","options":{"A":" will be ","B":" am\r\n","C":" might be ","D":" am going to be"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":546,"question":"“What are you doing tonight?”\r\n“I don’t know. I _____ out, or I _____ at home.”\r\n","options":{"A":" will go / am staying ","B":" might go / might stay\r\n","C":" am going / am staying ","D":" go / stay"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":547,"question":"We have guests coming for Saturday lunch. I _____ cook roast beef\r\nand Yorkshire pudding. I have bought all the ingredients.\r\n","options":{"A":" might ","B":" will ","C":" am going to cook ","D":" can"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":548,"question":"A- I’m going to buy George a green shirt.\r\nB- I wouldn’t if I were you.\r\nA- Why not?\r\nB- I’m sure he _____ the green color.\r\n","options":{"A":" might not like ","B":" will like\r\n","C":" isn’t going to like ","D":" won’t like"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":549,"question":"“Goodbye, darling. I _____ phone as soon as I arrive.”\r\n“Thanks. Bye!”\r\n","options":{"A":" can ","B":" will ","C":" am going to ","D":" might"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":550,"question":"Catherine wants to be a politician. Who knows? One day she ____\r\nPrime Minister!\r\n","options":{"A":" is going to be ","B":" will be\r\n","C":" might be ","D":" is"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":551,"question":"_____ on your warm coat. It’s cold today.\r\n","options":{"A":" Try ","B":" Fill ","C":" Dress ","D":" Put"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":552,"question":"Could I _____ on these shoes, please?\r\nSize nine.\r\n","options":{"A":" look ","B":" put ","C":" try ","D":" turn"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":553,"question":"Don’t forget to _____ off the lights when you come to bed.\r\n","options":{"A":" down ","B":" turn ","C":" fall ","D":" fill"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":554,"question":"You look tired. Sit _____ and have a cup of tea.\r\n","options":{"A":" away ","B":" on ","C":" down ","D":" put"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":555,"question":"I’m looking for yesterday’s newspaper. Did you throw it _____?\r\n","options":{"A":" out ","B":" down ","C":" back ","D":" away"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":556,"question":"Turn _____ the music! It’s too loud!\r\n","options":{"A":" on ","B":" round ","C":" down ","D":" after\r\nLaura __(13)__ in a big city. If she lived in the country, she __(14)__\r\na dog. Laura __(15)__ a flat with three other girls. But if it __(16)__\r\npossible, she __(17)__ on her own. If she __(18)__ in the country, she\r\n__(19)__ a small cottage, and she __(20)__ her own flowers and\r\nvegetables. She __(21)__ by underground and __(22)__ shopping in\r\nbig department stores, but she __(23)__ this at all. If she __(24)__ in\r\nthe country she __(25)__ her bike, and she __(26)__ things in a small\r\nvillage shop."},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":557,"question":"","options":{"A":" was living ","B":" lived\r\n","C":" would like to live ","D":" lives"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":558,"question":"","options":{"A":" has ","B":" would have ","C":" had ","D":" will have"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":559,"question":"","options":{"A":" share ","B":" is sharing ","C":" shares ","D":" shared"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":560,"question":"","options":{"A":" will be ","B":" was ","C":" is ","D":" were"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":561,"question":"","options":{"A":" lives ","B":" is living ","C":" will be living ","D":" would live"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":562,"question":"","options":{"A":" was living ","B":" were living ","C":" is living ","D":" lived"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":563,"question":"","options":{"A":" will buy ","B":" is going to buy\r\n","C":" would buy ","D":" buys"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":564,"question":"","options":{"A":" grows ","B":" wants to grow\r\n","C":" will grow ","D":" would grow"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":565,"question":"","options":{"A":" is traveling ","B":" would travel\r\n","C":" travels ","D":" will travel"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":566,"question":"","options":{"A":" go ","B":" goes ","C":" is going ","D":" would go"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":567,"question":"","options":{"A":" likes ","B":" would like ","C":" doesn’t like ","D":" is liking"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":568,"question":"","options":{"A":" were ","B":" is ","C":" will be ","D":" would being"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":569,"question":"","options":{"A":" rides ","B":" rode ","C":" would ride ","D":" is riding"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":570,"question":"","options":{"A":" bought ","B":" would buy ","C":" buys ","D":" will buy"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":571,"question":"“What’s for supper?”\r\n“We _____ lamb. It’s in the oven.”\r\n","options":{"A":" might have ","B":" would have ","C":" had ","D":" are having"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":572,"question":"“What time are we eating?”\r\n“Don’t worry. It _____ ready before your TV program.”\r\n","options":{"A":" is ","B":" will be ","C":" might be ","D":" *"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":573,"question":"I’m going to the town tomorrow. I _____ lunch with Joe at 1.00.”\r\n","options":{"A":" will have ","B":" am having ","C":" might have ","D":" have"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":574,"question":"“Are you going to have a winter holiday this year?”\r\n“I _____. I haven’t decided yet.”\r\n","options":{"A":" am ","B":" might ","C":" am not ","D":" can’t"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":575,"question":"How do you _____ your parents?\r\n","options":{"A":" look forward to ","B":" look up a word\r\n","C":" get on with ","D":" look out"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":576,"question":"You shouldn’t smoke in here. Put _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" it off ","B":" it down ","C":" it out ","D":" it away"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":577,"question":"I haven’t get time to fill in this form. I’ll fill _____ later.\r\n","options":{"A":" it ","B":" in it ","C":" on it ","D":" *"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":578,"question":"I _____ tennis tomorrow. But I’m not sure.\r\n","options":{"A":" play ","B":" am playing ","C":" will play ","D":" might play"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":579,"question":"If I ____ younger, I ____ to play the piano, but I’m too old now.\r\n","options":{"A":" am / will learn ","B":" will be / are learning\r\n","C":" were / would ","D":" were / would learn"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":580,"question":"I’m _____ forward to meeting her very much.\r\n","options":{"A":" fallen ","B":" looking ","C":" trying ","D":" giving"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":581,"question":"She _____ off her horse and hurt her wrist.\r\n","options":{"A":" put ","B":" turned ","C":" ran ","D":" fell"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":582,"question":"What a pretty dress! Turn _____ ! Let me look at it from the back.\r\n","options":{"A":" up ","B":" round ","C":" away ","D":" on"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":583,"question":"Don’t worry about the baby. I’ll look _____ her while you’re out.\r\n","options":{"A":" for ","B":" with ","C":" to ","D":" after"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":584,"question":"Pick _____ your litter! Don’t drop it on the street!\r\n","options":{"A":" on ","B":" up ","C":" out ","D":" back"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":585,"question":"If I _____ Prime Minister, I _____ increase tax for rich people.\r\n","options":{"A":" would be / shall ","B":" will be / will\r\n","C":" am / would ","D":" were / would"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":586,"question":"If I _____ in a big house, I _____ a party.\r\n","options":{"A":" lived / would have ","B":" am / am having\r\n","C":" will live / have ","D":" would live / will have"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":587,"question":"Thank you for the invitation. _____ I can’t come.\r\n","options":{"A":" Suddenly ","B":" Upstairs\r\n","C":" Unfortunately ","D":" Hardly"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":588,"question":"If she _____ a lot of clothes, she _____ money.\r\n","options":{"A":" bought / would have ","B":" would buy / has\r\n","C":" wouldn’t bought / had ","D":" didn’t buy / would have"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":589,"question":"If he _____ a watch, he _____ always late.\r\n","options":{"A":" will have / won’t be ","B":" had / isn’t\r\n","C":" has / is ","D":" had / wouldn’t be"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":590,"question":"They _____ their baby Lily, but they aren’t sure yet.\r\n","options":{"A":" will call ","B":" are calling ","C":" call ","D":" might call"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":591,"question":"I’d visit you more often if you _____ so far away.\r\n","options":{"A":" will be living ","B":" didn’t live\r\n","C":" don’t live ","D":" wouldn’t live"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":592,"question":"If I _____ perfect English, I _____ in this class.\r\n","options":{"A":" could spoke / won’t be ","B":" can speak / would be\r\n","C":" could speak / wouldn’t be ","D":" can’t speak / will not be"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":593,"question":"I _____ to work if I _____ better, but I feel terrible.\r\n","options":{"A":" went / felt ","B":" would go / feel\r\n","C":" will go / feel ","D":" would go / felt"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":594,"question":"What _____ if a stranger _____ you £1 million?\r\n","options":{"A":" will you do / gave ","B":" would you do / gave\r\n","C":" do you do / will give ","D":" would you do / will give\r\n"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":595,"question":"How long _____ in Paris?\r\n","options":{"A":" do you live ","B":" are you living\r\n","C":" have you been living ","D":" you live"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":596,"question":"Anna _____ a good job.\r\n","options":{"A":" finds ","B":" has found\r\n","C":" founded ","D":" has been finding"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":597,"question":"Pete and I _____ for over six months.\r\n","options":{"A":" are gone ","B":" have gone out\r\n","C":" went out ","D":" have been going out"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":598,"question":"I _____ a new flat a few months ago.\r\n","options":{"A":" bought ","B":" have been buying\r\n","C":" have bought ","D":" buy"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":599,"question":"How long _____ your car?\r\n","options":{"A":" have you had ","B":" you have\r\n","C":" are you have ","D":" have you been having"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":600,"question":"Tom _____ as a postman for the past month.\r\n","options":{"A":" has worked ","B":" worked\r\n","C":" works ","D":" has been working"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":601,"question":"I _____ an essay all day.\r\n","options":{"A":" write ","B":" have been written\r\n","C":" am writing ","D":" have been writing"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":602,"question":"I _____ six pages.\r\n","options":{"A":" am written ","B":" have been writing\r\n","C":" have written ","D":" write"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":603,"question":"“Are you going out?”\r\n“_____. I don’t know yet.”\r\n","options":{"A":" Carefully ","B":" Possibly ","C":" Mainly ","D":" Nearly"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":604,"question":"The exam was _____ difficult. I couldn’t do any of it.\r\n","options":{"A":" fluently ","B":" seriously ","C":" exactly ","D":" real"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":605,"question":"“How old are you?”\r\n“I’m _____ eight. It’s my birthday next week.”\r\n","options":{"A":" possibly ","B":" fluently ","C":" nearly ","D":" exactly"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":606,"question":"I travel a lot in my job, _____ to Europe.\r\n","options":{"A":" exactly ","B":" nearly ","C":" really ","D":" mainly"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":607,"question":"Sorry I’m late. _____ for a long time?\r\n","options":{"A":" Did you wait ","B":" Have you waited\r\n","C":" Have you been waiting ","D":" Did you wait"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":608,"question":"The streets are wet. _____?\r\n","options":{"A":" Was it raining ","B":" Has it been raining\r\n","C":" Has it rained ","D":" Did it rain"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":609,"question":"I’m hot because I _____!\r\n","options":{"A":" have run ","B":" run\r\n","C":" have been running ","D":" am run"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":610,"question":"I _____ my finger! It really hurts.\r\n","options":{"A":" cut ","B":" cutted\r\n","C":" have cut ","D":" have been cutting"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":611,"question":"_____ Paul Simon’s latest record?\r\n","options":{"A":" Have you heard ","B":" Have you been hearing\r\n","C":" Did you hear ","D":" Are you heard"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":612,"question":"She’s tired because she _____ all day.\r\n","options":{"A":" shopped ","B":" shops\r\n","C":" has been shopping ","D":" has shopped"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":613,"question":"Sorry. I _____ one of your glasses.\r\n","options":{"A":" have broken ","B":" broke\r\n","C":" break ","D":" have been breaking"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":614,"question":"How long _____ this book?\r\n","options":{"A":" do you read ","B":" are you reading\r\n","C":" have you been reading ","D":" have you read"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":615,"question":"They _____ here for three years.\r\n","options":{"A":" lives ","B":" are living\r\n","C":" live ","D":" have been living"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":616,"question":"I _____ the living room, but I haven’t finished yet.\r\n","options":{"A":" have painted ","B":" paint\r\n","C":" painted ","D":" have been painting"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":617,"question":"I _____ my wallet. Where did I last put it?\r\n","options":{"A":" lost ","B":" have lost\r\n","C":" have been losing ","D":" lose"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":618,"question":"Look what Pat _____ me for my birthday! A bike!\r\n","options":{"A":" gave ","B":" have been giving\r\n","C":" gives ","D":" has given"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":619,"question":"There’s my wallet! I _____ for it for ages.\r\n","options":{"A":" have been looking ","B":" looked\r\n","C":" have looked ","D":" look\r\nWe __(26)__ in our new house for several months. Since we __(27)__\r\nin, we __(28)__ very busy. Everyone __(29)__ to get the house ready.\r\nSo far we __(30)__ the living room and the kitchen. Soon after we\r\narrived the central heating __(31)__ down, so we __(32)__ to spend\r\na lot of money to repair it.\r\nWe __(33)__ gardening very much, but we __(34)__ time to do\r\nanything in the garden yet. And it __(35)__ very heavily recently, so\r\nwe’ll just wait till the weather gets better."},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":620,"question":"","options":{"A":" lives ","B":" lived\r\n","C":" have lived ","D":" have been living"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":621,"question":"","options":{"A":" have moved ","B":" moved\r\n","C":" have been moving ","D":" are moving"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":622,"question":"","options":{"A":" are ","B":" have been being\r\n","C":" were ","D":" have been"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":623,"question":"","options":{"A":" has been helping ","B":" has helped\r\n","C":" helps ","D":" helped"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":624,"question":"","options":{"A":" decorated ","B":" decorate\r\n","C":" have decorated ","D":" have decorating"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":625,"question":"","options":{"A":" have broken ","B":" broke\r\n","C":" breaks ","D":" are breaking"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":626,"question":"","options":{"A":" have been having ","B":" have\r\n","C":" had ","D":" have had"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":627,"question":"","options":{"A":" are liking ","B":" liked ","C":" have liked ","D":" like"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":628,"question":"","options":{"A":" don’t have ","B":" haven’t had ","C":" had not ","D":" aren’t having"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":629,"question":"","options":{"A":" is raining ","B":" rained\r\n","C":" have been raining ","D":" has rained"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":630,"question":"“Can I speak to Mr. Thompson, please?”\r\n“I’m afraid he’s just _____ out of the office.”\r\n","options":{"A":" been ","B":" has ","C":" gone ","D":" *"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":631,"question":"I _____ to most countries in Europe, but I’ve never _____ to Russia.\r\n","options":{"A":" was / gone ","B":" have gone / been\r\n","C":" have been / been ","D":" went / gone"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":632,"question":"_____ me that you’ll always tell the truth.\r\n","options":{"A":" Advise ","B":" Waste ","C":" Promise ","D":" Invent"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":633,"question":"He was taken to hospital by ambulance, but he was _____ on arrival.\r\n","options":{"A":" mad ","B":" dead ","C":" alive ","D":" various"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":634,"question":"I love the _____ and quite of the countryside.\r\n","options":{"A":" peace ","B":" feeling ","C":" comfort ","D":" wealth"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":635,"question":"I saw a(n) _____ for a job as a waiter.\r\n","options":{"A":" invention ","B":" mystery\r\n","C":" waste ","D":" advertisement"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":636,"question":"The sofa was so ______ that I felt asleep.\r\n","options":{"A":" successful ","B":" comfortable ","C":" honest ","D":" comforting"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":637,"question":"I gave the police a(n) _____ of the man who attacked me.\r\n","options":{"A":" beauty ","B":" describing ","C":" advice ","D":" description"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":638,"question":"I had a few problems, but Bob gave me some good _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" advice ","B":" promises ","C":" inventions ","D":" *"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":639,"question":"I was sitting at home when suddenly I had a funny _____ that I\r\nwasn’t alone.\r\n","options":{"A":" belief ","B":" government ","C":" mystery ","D":" feeling"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":640,"question":"I used to speak French _____, but I’ve forgotten it now.\r\n","options":{"A":" successfully ","B":" fluently ","C":" honestly ","D":" carefully"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":641,"question":"Please drive _____. The roads are so dangerous.\r\n","options":{"A":" carefully ","B":" seriously ","C":" comfortably ","D":" wealthy"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":642,"question":"I have _____ £5.17 until the end of the week.\r\n","options":{"A":" exactly ","B":" suddenly ","C":" peacefully ","D":" really"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":643,"question":"There was an accident, but fortunately no one was _____ injured.\r\n","options":{"A":" mainly ","B":" seriously ","C":" possibly ","D":" exactly"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":644,"question":"“Where does their money come from?”\r\n“They have a very _____ business.”\r\n","options":{"A":" wealthy ","B":" comfortable ","C":" successful ","D":" various\r\n"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":645,"question":"Lisa _____ me a lift because I _____ the bus.\r\n","options":{"A":" gave / missed ","B":" have given / have missed\r\n","C":" gave / had missed ","D":" had gave / missed"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":646,"question":"I _____ her for everything she _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" thanking / did ","B":" thanked / had done\r\n","C":" have thanked / has done ","D":" had thanked / had done"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":647,"question":"When I got to the office, I _____ that I _____ to lock the front door.\r\n","options":{"A":" had realized / forget ","B":" realized / had forgotten\r\n","C":" realized / forget ","D":" had realized / had forgotten"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":648,"question":"After they _____ their work, they ___ home.\r\n","options":{"A":" had finished / went ","B":" finished / went\r\n","C":" had finished / had gone ","D":" finished / had gone"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":649,"question":"I _____ you at 8.00, but you _____ just _____ out.\r\n","options":{"A":" call / have / gone ","B":" called / have / gone\r\n","C":" called / had / gone ","D":" have called / have / gone"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":650,"question":"I took my family to Paris last year. I _____ there as a student, so I\r\n_____ my way around.\r\n","options":{"A":" was / know ","B":" were / knew\r\n","C":" had been / have known ","D":" had been / knew"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":651,"question":"After I _____ to the news, I _____ to bed.\r\n","options":{"A":" listened / went ","B":" had listened / went\r\n","C":" have listened / had gone ","D":" listen / go"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":652,"question":"He _____ he was at school the day before.\r\n","options":{"A":" says ","B":" told ","C":" said ","D":" is telling"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":653,"question":"Sandra _____ Bob that she didn’t see the Taj Mahal.\r\n","options":{"A":" told ","B":" tells ","C":" said ","D":" talked"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":654,"question":"Why did you _____ that?\r\n","options":{"A":" talk ","B":" said ","C":" tell ","D":" say"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":655,"question":"Could I ______ your pen?\r\n","options":{"A":" give ","B":" lend ","C":" borrow ","D":" make"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":656,"question":"I’m English. I come from Brighton. In Paris I am a _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" cooker ","B":" stranger ","C":" travel ","D":" foreigner\r\nI went to a school reunion last week. I __(13)__ very surprised. So\r\nmany things __(14)__. They __(15)__ the old gymnasium, and the\r\nlibrary __(16)__. I __(17)__ slowly round the school. Everything\r\n__(18)__ much smaller, although they __(19)__ some impressive new\r\nbuildings. I __(20)__ lots of my old schools friends, too, and they\r\n__(21)__ the same either. Some of them __(22)__ to London, and\r\nthe most of them __(23)__ married. I __(24)__ to the headmaster for\r\na while. He __(25)__. He __(26)__ that he __(27)__ every boy who\r\n__(28)__ the school since he __(29)__ working there in 1978. But\r\nwhen I asked him what my name was, he __(30)__ confess that he\r\n__(31)__ which __(32)__ me realize that I __(33)__ too!"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":657,"question":"","options":{"A":" am ","B":" have been ","C":" was ","D":" had been"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":658,"question":"","options":{"A":" changed ","B":" had changed\r\n","C":" has changed ","D":" has change"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":659,"question":"","options":{"A":" had knocked down ","B":" knocked down\r\n","C":" knock down ","D":" have knocked down"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":660,"question":"","options":{"A":" disappeared ","B":" was disappeared\r\n","C":" had disappeared ","D":" have been disappeared"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":661,"question":"","options":{"A":" have walked ","B":" walked\r\n","C":" was walking ","D":" had walked"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":662,"question":"","options":{"A":" seems ","B":" have seemed\r\n","C":" had seemed ","D":" seemed"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":663,"question":"","options":{"A":" were building ","B":" built\r\n","C":" have built ","D":" had built"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":664,"question":"","options":{"A":" met ","B":" meet ","C":" had met ","D":" have meet"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":665,"question":"","options":{"A":" hadn’t stayed ","B":" weren’t stayed\r\n","C":" didn’t stay ","D":" not stayed"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":666,"question":"","options":{"A":" have moved ","B":" moved\r\n","C":" had moved ","D":" was moving"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":667,"question":"","options":{"A":" are get ","B":" had got ","C":" were got ","D":" have got"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":668,"question":"","options":{"A":" talked ","B":" had talked ","C":" was talking ","D":" have talked"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":669,"question":"","options":{"A":" haven’t left ","B":" had not left\r\n","C":" didn’t leave ","D":" hadn’t leave"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":670,"question":"","options":{"A":" said ","B":" was saying ","C":" had said ","D":" have said"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":671,"question":"","options":{"A":" remembers ","B":" have remembered\r\n","C":" remembered ","D":" had remembered"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":672,"question":"","options":{"A":" attended ","B":" had attended\r\n","C":" have attended ","D":" attending"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":673,"question":"","options":{"A":" had started ","B":" starts ","C":" started ","D":" have started"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":674,"question":"","options":{"A":" had to ","B":" have had to ","C":" had had to ","D":" was having to"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":675,"question":"","options":{"A":" forget ","B":" forgot\r\n","C":" have forgotten ","D":" had forgotten"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":676,"question":"","options":{"A":" have made ","B":" made ","C":" had made ","D":" was made"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":677,"question":"","options":{"A":" was changed ","B":" had changed\r\n","C":" have changed ","D":" changed"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":678,"question":"_____ I had had a bath I went to bed.\r\n","options":{"A":" Before ","B":" Soon as ","C":" After ","D":" Until"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":679,"question":"I had read the book _____ I saw the film.\r\n","options":{"A":" when ","B":" before ","C":" until ","D":" after"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":680,"question":"I ____ to sleep until I _____ my homework.\r\n","options":{"A":" don’t go / did ","B":" had not gone / had done\r\n","C":" didn’t go / did ","D":" didn’t go / had done"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":681,"question":"As soon as he _____ his driving test, he _____ a car.\r\n","options":{"A":" passed / bought ","B":" had passed / bought\r\n","C":" passes / had bought ","D":" passed / had bought"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":682,"question":"When I _____ the letter, I _____ it away.\r\n","options":{"A":" read / had thrown ","B":" had read / had thrown\r\n","C":" had read / threw ","D":" read / threw"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":683,"question":"“You can move in immediately.”\r\nShe told me I _____ immediately.\r\n","options":{"A":" will move in ","B":" would move in\r\n","C":" can move in ","D":" could move in"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":684,"question":"“The people who I looked after are very well.”\r\nShe said that the people who she _____ after _____ very well.\r\n","options":{"A":" were looking / are ","B":" have looked / are\r\n","C":" would looked / were ","D":" had looked / were"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":685,"question":"“You’ll have to make up your mind soon.”\r\nShe told me I _____ make up my mind soon.\r\n","options":{"A":" had to ","B":" will have had to\r\n","C":" would have to ","D":" could have to"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"D"},{"questionNumber":686,"question":"I didn’t recognize him because he _____ a haircut.\r\n","options":{"A":" had had ","B":" has ","C":" had ","D":" have had"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":687,"question":"He always makes me _____.\r\n","options":{"A":" to laugh ","B":" laughing ","C":" laugh ","D":" be laughed"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"A"},{"questionNumber":688,"question":"She refused _____ for the meal.\r\n","options":{"A":" paying ","B":" to pay ","C":" pays ","D":" the pay"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":689,"question":"I’ll never forget _____ him for the first time.\r\n","options":{"A":" meet ","B":" meeting ","C":" to meet ","D":" to met"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":690,"question":"“It’s a quite flat, and the neighbors are nice.”\r\n“Mrs. Deon said it __a quite flat, and the neighbors __ nice.”\r\n","options":{"A":" has been / are ","B":" is / were\r\n","C":" was / were ","D":" had been / have been"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":691,"question":"“You look brown. Have you ____ on holiday?”\r\n“Yes, we’ve _____ got back.”\r\n","options":{"A":" been / now ","B":" gone / just\r\n","C":" been / just ","D":" did / already"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":692,"question":"I live in a house now, but before I _____ in a flat.\r\n","options":{"A":" am using to live ","B":" used to live\r\n","C":" had used to live ","D":" have used to live"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"},{"questionNumber":693,"question":"“I need £100 deposit.”\r\nThen she said she _____ £100 deposit.\r\n","options":{"A":" needs ","B":" had needed\r\n","C":" needed ","D":" have needed"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"B"},{"questionNumber":694,"question":"I _____ the book back to the library after I _____ reading it.\r\n","options":{"A":" take / finished ","B":" have taken / have finished\r\n","C":" took / had finished ","D":" had taken / finished\r\n"},"questionClass":"Grammar","questionLevel":"pre-intermediate","answer":"C"}]